<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-03T11:54:09-05:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Beacon</title><subtitle>The Beacon is Martingrove's newspaper.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Article of Awesome</title><link href="/2019/11/Article_of_Awesome.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Article of Awesome" /><published>2019-11-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-11-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2019/11/Article_of_Awesome</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/11/Article_of_Awesome.html">&lt;p&gt;Although school is important, it can get quite long and repetitive
sometimes. It’s the same classes every other day for 10 months straight,
so we tend to get stuck in a boring routine: school, homework, sleep,
repeat. It's difficult to find pleasure in the school stuff we do, so
we turn to other things, like entertainment, media, sports, and the
arts. So, while you’re sitting in whatever class right now, here are 15
awesome everyday things to think about. I hope they may cheer you up, or
make your outlook on life a little more positive, without the feelings
of stress, anxiety and craziness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sleeping in a bed with fresh sheets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Looking in the fridge/pantry and seeing your favourite snack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The feeling of a soft rug under your bare feet &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The buzz after you’ve just posted a new picture on social media, and
see the positive comments start rolling in&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The smell of freshly baked cookies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finishing that thing you’ve been procrastinating about for a long
time &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Naturally waking up early, without an alarm &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally eating the food you’ve been craving forever&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When someone asks, “How was your day?” and you actually have
good/eventful news to share &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having a good hair day &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cracking a joke and making everyone laugh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you randomly reach out to a friend to see if they’re free and
they are&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The movie theatre lights dimming, letting you know that the magic is
about to begin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being the one in your friend group who actually remembered the
homework&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The feeling of walking out of school on a Friday &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it! Just a few ordinary things that may make you smile,
or fill you with satisfaction. I hope these things give you the
motivation to conquer your day and remind you that there’s a lot to
enjoy in the world, so keep a lookout!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>smahmud</name></author><summary type="html">Although school is important, it can get quite long and repetitive sometimes. It’s the same classes every other day for 10 months straight, so we tend to get stuck in a boring routine: school, homework, sleep, repeat. It's difficult to find pleasure in the school stuff we do, so we turn to other things, like entertainment, media, sports, and the arts. So, while you’re sitting in whatever class right now, here are 15 awesome everyday things to think about. I hope they may cheer you up, or make your outlook on life a little more positive, without the feelings of stress, anxiety and craziness.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2019-11-03-Article_of_Awesome_photo.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Test Listicle</title><link href="/2019/10/test_beacon_listicle.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test Listicle" /><published>2019-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2019/10/test_beacon_listicle</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/10/test_beacon_listicle.html">&lt;p&gt;Dfsesfs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;fsdfsdfsdfsefefefe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First item
yeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayeayea&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Second item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thir
dfsdfefsrgfddfsdfefsrgfddfsdfefsrgfddfsdfefsrgfddfsdfefsrgfddfsdfefsrgfddfsdfefsrgfddfsdfefsrgfddfsdfefsrgfddfsdfefsrgfddfsdfefsrgfddfsdfefsrgfddfsdfefsrgfddfsdfefsrgfd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>cmac</name></author><summary type="html">Dfsesfs</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Whoop whoop announcement test</title><link href="/2019/05/test-announcement.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Whoop whoop announcement test" /><published>2019-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2019/05/test-announcement</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/05/test-announcement.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello irrybodie.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>srao</name></author><summary type="html">Hello irrybodie.</summary></entry></feed>