<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-04T11:50:57-04:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Beacon</title><subtitle>The Beacon is Martingrove's newspaper.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">MEC Environmental Column: How Bears Can Celebrate Earth Hour</title><link href="/2020/04/MEC_Environmental_Column_How_Bears_Can_Celebrate_Earth_Hour_-_Linda_Li-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MEC Environmental Column: How Bears Can Celebrate Earth Hour" /><published>2020-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2020/04/MEC_Environmental_Column_How_Bears_Can_Celebrate_Earth_Hour_-_Linda_Li-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/04/MEC_Environmental_Column_How_Bears_Can_Celebrate_Earth_Hour_-_Linda_Li-2.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey Bears! Earth Hour 2020 (&lt;strong&gt;Saturday March 28th, 2020, at 8:30 pm&lt;/strong&gt;)
is rapidly approaching. You probably already know what Earth Hour is,
and you might think that it’s somewhat silly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nobody actually believes that a bunch of people turning off some
lights for one hour is going to change anything, do they? And our school
can’t really participate anyway. The timing doesn’t allow it and if we
turn off our lights, the school will be plunged into darkness.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, it is an unfortunate truth that MCI’s notorious lack of windows
and natural lighting makes it difficult for us to celebrate Earth Hour.
And yes, we obviously can’t “properly” participate because there’s no
school on the 28th. There won’t ever be school during Earth Hour, since
it takes place in the evening and on the last Saturday of March.
Regardless, MCI and many other schools do their bit on the Friday
before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the question still remains - does Earth Hour make a difference?
According to the mission statement of EarthHour.org, (the official
website for… well, Earth Hour), the main purpose of Earth Hour is to
make a symbolic commitment to the betterment of our environment. The
event is meant to “spark global conversations on protecting nature not
only to combat the climate crisis, but to ensure our own health,
happiness, prosperity and even survival.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The carbon emission reduction of the event is indeed negligible (Gollom,
2014), but millions of people across 180 countries participate in Earth
Hour every year, meaning they have taken the time out of their day to
consider how they as individuals can impact the planet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, Earth Hour is simplistic. Anyone can do it and the second it’s
over, we can continue on with our wasteful, energy-guzzling, consumer
lifestyles. But for that brief hour, people are acting in unity for our
environment. Any act of positive unity in our increasingly more
complicated society is a moment to be cherished. So if you can, please
do consider participating in Earth Hour 2020 with your families and
conserve energy whenever possible to carry on the spirit of
environmental stewardship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy conservation tips include: turning off lights that are not in
use, unplugging appliances that are not in use (yeah it’s annoying to
plug them in again, but come on! That’s a first world problem if I ever
heard one) and changing to energy efficient lights and appliances (this
tip does depend on how cool your parents are, of course). The internet
is at your fingertips for more information on how you can make a
difference, of course. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Earth Hour, MCI!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Source: &lt;em&gt;NASA Earth Observatory/Joshua Stevens; NOAA National
Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information Service.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>lli</name></author><summary type="html">Hey Bears! Earth Hour 2020 (Saturday March 28th, 2020, at 8:30 pm) is rapidly approaching. You probably already know what Earth Hour is, and you might think that it’s somewhat silly. </summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2020-04-04-MEC_Environmental_Column_How_Bears_Can_Celebrate_Earth_Hour_-_Linda_Li-2_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">MEC Environmental Column: How Bears Can Celebrate Earth Hour</title><link href="/2020/04/MEC_Environmental_Column_How_Bears_Can_Celebrate_Earth_Hour_-_Linda_Li.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MEC Environmental Column: How Bears Can Celebrate Earth Hour" /><published>2020-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2020/04/MEC_Environmental_Column_How_Bears_Can_Celebrate_Earth_Hour_-_Linda_Li</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/04/MEC_Environmental_Column_How_Bears_Can_Celebrate_Earth_Hour_-_Linda_Li.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey Bears! Earth Hour 2020 (&lt;strong&gt;Saturday March 28th, 2020, at 8:30 pm&lt;/strong&gt;)
is rapidly approaching. You probably already know what Earth Hour is,
and you might think that it’s somewhat silly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nobody actually believes that a bunch of people turning off some
lights for one hour is going to change anything, do they? And our school
can’t really participate anyway. The timing doesn’t allow it and if we
turn off our lights, the school will be plunged into darkness.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, it is an unfortunate truth that MCI’s notorious lack of windows
and natural lighting makes it difficult for us to celebrate Earth Hour.
And yes, we obviously can’t “properly” participate because there’s no
school on the 28th. There won’t ever be school during Earth Hour, since
it takes place in the evening and on the last Saturday of March.
Regardless, MCI and many other schools do their bit on the Friday
before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the question still remains - does Earth Hour make a difference?
According to the mission statement of EarthHour.org, (the official
website for… well, Earth Hour), the main purpose of Earth Hour is to
make a symbolic commitment to the betterment of our environment. The
event is meant to “spark global conversations on protecting nature not
only to combat the climate crisis, but to ensure our own health,
happiness, prosperity and even survival.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The carbon emission reduction of the event is indeed negligible (Gollom,
2014), but millions of people across 180 countries participate in Earth
Hour every year, meaning they have taken the time out of their day to
consider how they as individuals can impact the planet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, Earth Hour is simplistic. Anyone can do it and the second it’s
over, we can continue on with our wasteful, energy-guzzling, consumer
lifestyles. But for that brief hour, people are acting in unity for our
environment. Any act of positive unity in our increasingly more
complicated society is a moment to be cherished. So if you can, please
do consider participating in Earth Hour 2020 with your families and
conserve energy whenever possible to carry on the spirit of
environmental stewardship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy conservation tips include: turning off lights that are not in
use, unplugging appliances that are not in use (yeah it’s annoying to
plug them in again, but come on! That’s a first world problem if I ever
heard one) and changing to energy efficient lights and appliances (this
tip does depend on how cool your parents are, of course). The internet
is at your fingertips for more information on how you can make a
difference, of course. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Earth Hour, MCI!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Source: &lt;em&gt;NASA Earth Observatory/Joshua Stevens; NOAA National
Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information Service.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>lli</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Hey Bears! Earth Hour 2020 (Saturday March 28th, 2020, at 8:30 pm) is rapidly approaching. You probably already know what Earth Hour is, and you might think that it’s somewhat silly. </summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2020-04-04-MEC_Environmental_Column_How_Bears_Can_Celebrate_Earth_Hour_-_Linda_Li_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Year in Review: Ranking My Top 10 Films of 2019</title><link href="/2020/02/File.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Year in Review: Ranking My Top 10 Films of 2019" /><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/02/File</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/02/File.html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past twelve months, we were handed a diverse collection of
films. Be it comedies, thrillers, action movies, or dramas, filmmakers
new and old raised the bar for this medium in 2019. As the year comes to
an end, I am taking a look back and ranking my top ten movies of the
year. I chose the films that challenged me as a viewer, made me think
for days after I watched it, and most importantly, films that were just
really fun to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10. &lt;strong&gt;Climax&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Gasper Noé &lt;em&gt;Climax&lt;/em&gt; follows a group of aspiring
dancers in an abandoned school, as their rehearsal spirals out of
control into madness. This film is a visually stunning, yet disturbing
erotic rush from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9. &lt;strong&gt;Shazam!&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. David F. Sandberg From DC Comics, &lt;em&gt;Shazam&lt;/em&gt;! follows
14-year-old Billy Batson as he must learn how to deal with God-like
superpowers. With family values at the core of this film and a stellar
child cast, Shazam! is the most heartwarming superhero film of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8. &lt;strong&gt;Ad Astra&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. James Gray Brad Pitt soars in this film which
explores the powerful bond between a father and son. Cinematographer
Hoyte van Hoytema delivers a visual spectacle of outer space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7. &lt;strong&gt;The Peanut Butter Falcon&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Tyler Nilson, Michael Schwartz A
young man with down syndrome escapes his nursing facility with dreams of
attending a wrestling school. Shia LaBeouf is mesmerizing in this
charming homage to a Mark Twain classic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6. &lt;strong&gt;Midsommar&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Ari Aster &lt;em&gt;Midsommar&lt;/em&gt; is a confusing, thought
provoking, and ambitious film. Director Ari Aster creates another
masterfully crafted horror film that almost rivals Aster’s previous
classic, Hereditary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. &lt;strong&gt;The Lighthouse&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Robert Eggers Robert Pattinson and Willem
Dafoe give strong performances in this wicked tale of two lighthouse
keepers on a distant island in New England. Robert Eggers really
solidifies himself as a strong filmmaker in the horror genre with this
film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;Rocketman&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Dexter Fletcher Taron Egerton gives his best
performance yet with &lt;em&gt;Rocketman&lt;/em&gt;. I think it's going to be a long long
time until another film succeeds in creating a movie musical biopic as
intense as &lt;em&gt;Rocketman&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Booksmart&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Olivia Wilde Olivia Wilde’s directorial debut is a
coming-of-age comedy between two best friends and academic
‘overachievers’ who realize that they’ve wasted their high school years
slaving away instead of having fun. &lt;em&gt;Booksmart&lt;/em&gt; is a wild and fast-paced
movie that is clever in its portrayal of teenagers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Joker&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Todd Phillips &lt;em&gt;Joker&lt;/em&gt; is a heartbreaking and brutal
take on the clown prince of crime’s origin story. Todd Phillips draws
heavy inspiration from films such as Taxi Driver and The King of Comedy
to construct his tale of a man disregarded by society. Phillips’s Gotham
is corrupt and crime ridden, but it’s the realism that helps amplify the
film’s critique of a society that dismisses its citizens. Joaquin
Phoenix gives a disturbing performance as Arthur Fleck that at times may
call on the viewer to sympathize with him but strictly acknowledges his
vile actions. Todd Phillip’s direction and Lawrence Sher’s beautiful
cinematography accompanied by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?rlz=1C1CHBF_enCA725CA725&amp;amp;sxsrf=ACYBGNQuXgS18sMnW0dR0f5xf7FY-3OGsg:1573864416354&amp;amp;q=Hildur+Gu%C3%B0nad%C3%B3ttir&amp;amp;stick=H4sIAAAAAAAAAONgVuLSz9U3MKoyTMvIe8Toyi3w8sc9YSmbSWtOXmM04-IKzsgvd80rySypFNLgYoOy5Lj4pJC0aTBI8XAh8XkWsYp4ZOaklBYpuJce3pCXmHJ4c0lJZhEAfHynQG0AAAA&quot;&gt;Hildur
Guðnadóttir&lt;/a&gt;’s
hypnotizing score help make &lt;em&gt;Joker&lt;/em&gt; standout film from 2019 that must be
viewed more than once to fully grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Parasite&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Bong Joon-ho Bong Joon-ho’s &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt; is
undoubtedly 2019’s must see film. Every aspect of this film from its
cast to its cinematography is fantastic. &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt;’s depiction of
themes of class, wealth, and dignity are apparent but not in your face.
Joon-ho’s slow yet persistent race to the end will keep you on the edge
of your seat. &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt; follows the extremely poor Kim family as they
launch an all-out assault on the blatantly wealthy Park family. When
Kim’s son, Ki-Woo, secures a job as a tutor for the daughter of the Park
family, he opens the door for the rest of his family to infiltrate the
Park’s home. The Kim family makes quick work of ridding the Park
family’s employees and securing their jobs through tactical and cunning
plans. Each member of the Kim family has a moment to shine. The film
starts off presenting itself as a satirical comedy but takes a jarring
turn into brutality. The film spirals out of control in front of your
eyes and you are forced to view every disturbing second of it. Bong’s
mastery of the camera and formulation of violence is electrifying in
&lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt;. This film is truly an unforgettable piece of cinema will be
deconstructed, examined, and celebrated for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/50048137@N00/8442936606&quot;&gt;&quot;Welcome To The
Theater&quot;&lt;/a&gt; by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/50048137@N00&quot;&gt;rsmithing&lt;/a&gt; is licensed
under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;amp;atype=rich&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC 2.0
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ifuse-katayama</name></author><summary type="html">Over the past twelve months, we were handed a diverse collection of films. Be it comedies, thrillers, action movies, or dramas, filmmakers new and old raised the bar for this medium in 2019. As the year comes to an end, I am taking a look back and ranking my top ten movies of the year. I chose the films that challenged me as a viewer, made me think for days after I watched it, and most importantly, films that were just really fun to watch.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2020-02-01-File_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">All the Ways to Cope with Your Seasonal Depression This Winter</title><link href="/2020/02/File_1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=" All the Ways to Cope with Your Seasonal Depression This Winter" /><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/02/File_1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/02/File_1.html">&lt;p&gt;The snow-covered street, the fear of slipping on black ice on the floor,
the hope of waking up to it being a snow day are all Toronto’s ways of
saying it is here: the winter season. Gone (too soon) are the orange and
brown leafy streets, the comforting sweater weather, the therapeutic
feeling of ordering a pumpkin spice latte albeit it's horrendous taste.
Before those moments, we enjoyed the hot air, the feeling of no school,
the beach outings, picnics in the parks, the gorgeous sunsets, the
beautiful long days, and the alluring shorts nights. Now, we must endure
this horrible winter season. Does this sound a little melodramatic?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is exactly how the winter season feels for those who suffer from
Seasonal Affective Disorder. Otherwise known as SAD or seasonal
depression, Seasonal Affective Disorder only affects 15% of Canadians
who tend to experience a milder version of SAD. Although it might sound
rare, it's important for everyone to know what it is in case it every
happens to yourself or a loved one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who don’t know what Seasonal Affective Disorder (&lt;strong&gt;SAD&lt;/strong&gt;) is,
it is simply a type of depression that relates to changes in seasons.
Although most people have SAD starting at the end of fall or the
beginning and continue well into the end of winter, some do have it
after winter and during the summer season. It can lead to low energy,
moodiness, and a lack of motivation. For many people, SAD mostly
consists of wanting to stay in bed and doing nothing the entire day. It
can feel never-ending but here are a few things to combat your seasonal
depression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Sun Lamp:&lt;/strong&gt; This lamp gives off a bright light that mimics natural
outdoor light. It also helps with other types of depression, sleep
disorders or other skin conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distract yourself:&lt;/strong&gt; Activities include: hanging out with loved ones,
listening to a thrilling podcast, trying a new hobby or even starting a
new book or a television series. All of these can help take your mind
off of your depression and make your life feel better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talk to a loved one:&lt;/strong&gt; It can be hard to express your feelings to a
loved one, but it always helps to know you’re not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winter blues might take a toll on you every year, but we’re hoping
that you pull through this year with the help of some of these tips or
even pure perseverance. Either way, we have faith in you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Source:
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/23969527@N05/3167454902&quot;&gt;&quot;Winter&quot;&lt;/a&gt; by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/23969527@N05&quot;&gt;abaransk&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under
&lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;amp;atype=rich&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC-ND 2.0
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>hnur</name></author><summary type="html">The snow-covered street, the fear of slipping on black ice on the floor, the hope of waking up to it being a snow day are all Toronto’s ways of saying it is here: the winter season. Gone (too soon) are the orange and brown leafy streets, the comforting sweater weather, the therapeutic feeling of ordering a pumpkin spice latte albeit it's horrendous taste. Before those moments, we enjoyed the hot air, the feeling of no school, the beach outings, picnics in the parks, the gorgeous sunsets, the beautiful long days, and the alluring shorts nights. Now, we must endure this horrible winter season. Does this sound a little melodramatic?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2020-02-01-File_1_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My New Year’s Resolutions</title><link href="/2020/02/File_2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=" My New Year’s Resolutions" /><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/02/File_2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/02/File_2.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about my New Year’s Resolutions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I think it’s time for some internal revolutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got my own problems and I’m looking for solutions,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So below are some points for my self-evolution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm getting blackout curtains to keep out the light pollution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m baby-proofing outlets to prevent electrocution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll use applesauce for eggs and master substitution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll fight my wrongful arrest, escaping persecution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love my rights and freedoms so I’ll read the Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salty water’s pretty great so I’m buying saline solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll expand my vocabulary; learn new words like &lt;em&gt;collocution.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll visit &lt;em&gt;Doctors Without Borders&lt;/em&gt;, and make my contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t leave people out, I’ll never be one to shun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That last line was pretty bad, I could have used “exclusion”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wanted another verse, sorry for the confusion,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is now the end- you’ve now reached the conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/24230475@N04/2333965284&quot;&gt;&quot;birthday
balloons&quot;&lt;/a&gt; by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/24230475@N04&quot;&gt;mae.noelle&lt;/a&gt; is licensed
under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;amp;atype=rich&quot;&gt;CC BY-ND 2.0
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>srao</name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been thinking about my New Year’s Resolutions</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2020-02-01-File_2_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Do The Holidays Right!</title><link href="/2020/02/File_3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Do The Holidays Right!" /><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/02/File_3</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/02/File_3.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of year again! The holidays are upon us and the
festivities are going to begin (as soon as winter break comes and we’re
not studying for five tests every night)! After a long year you might be
looking back on fond memories or looking ahead in hopes of a better
year. Whatever the case, don’t forget to make the most of the time we
have left before 2020!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some suggestions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skate on an Ice Trail Through a Moonlit Forest!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;About two and a half hours north of the city is Arrowhead Provincial
Park. Why should you care? Well, if you’re a fan of skating or the
outdoors then this is the place to be! On the park’s Fire and Ice
nights (6pm to 9pm) you can skate down a picturesque trail through the
woods lit up by torches! It’s a promising and magical experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visit Toronto’s Christmas Market Ft. Victorian vibes!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Inspired by the European tradition of Christkindlmarkt, Toronto’s
Christmas Market in the cobblestone lined Distillery District is a
mecca for those looking to get into the holiday spirit. Be mesmerized
by the breathtaking lights and huge Christmas tree! Taste the
holidays! Browse the beautiful crafts and gifts! Hear the choirs and
music! It’s the ultimate festive experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch Some Holiday Movies!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;No doubt you’ve seen them countless times but I will watch ‘Home
Alone’ every year around the holidays, no matter what! ‘It's a
Wonderful Life’ and ‘A Charlie Brown Christmas’ are some other
favorites of mine! Curl up with some warm blankets, hot cocoa and some
friends / family!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all just enjoy yourself! You’ve all worked hard this year and
survived to tell the tale! Whether you’re resting up or going full on
party mode I hope you have a great winter break! Until the new year,
keep warm MCI! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/68089229@N06/22961506443&quot;&gt;&quot;Christmas
Tree&quot;&lt;/a&gt; by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/68089229@N06&quot;&gt;oatsy40&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under
&lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;amp;atype=rich&quot;&gt;CC BY 2.0
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>anaing</name></author><summary type="html">It’s that time of year again! The holidays are upon us and the festivities are going to begin (as soon as winter break comes and we’re not studying for five tests every night)! After a long year you might be looking back on fond memories or looking ahead in hopes of a better year. Whatever the case, don’t forget to make the most of the time we have left before 2020!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2020-02-01-File_3_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sleighing this Holiday Season</title><link href="/2020/02/File_4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sleighing this Holiday Season" /><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/02/File_4</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/02/File_4.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A guide to tree-ting this season right (filled with history,
controversies, and more!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has begun. Everyone has simultaneously agreed, as if some telepathic
phenomenon has occurred, and set out to accomplish one thing. 98.1 CHFI
has &lt;em&gt;Toronto’s Christmas Music Station&lt;/em&gt;; stores have transformed to fit
consumer holiday needs; Canada’s Wonderland has created Winterfest; and
so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the question comes to mind: are &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; completely prepared for
the holiday season? If you answered no, read this guide! If you answered
yes, read this guide!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ReSPECT; don’t ReGIFT!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regifting- although harmless when done thoughtfully- requires careful
attention and etiquette. There are certain rules one must pay heed to
when committing such an act. Firstly, never regift anything meaningful
or handmade. Doing this will transform you into a Grinch! Secondly,
regift outside of your circle of friends. This avoids awkward tension
and does not hurt the original gift-giver. Thirdly, regift
&lt;em&gt;thoughtfully.&lt;/em&gt; For example, you would not regift a Crock-Pot to your
7-year old brother; you would give it to your mom who is in need of one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When in doubt, regift to charity.” This saying avoids many conflicts
and is a solution towards a greater good. Simply storing the gift or
throwing it away because you got the Crock-Pot 99 instead of Crock-Pot
100, wastes many resources, time, and energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bake with a Canine Twist!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s that I smell in your oven? Dog cookies! They are the motive this
season. The world wide web consists of numerous recipes that you can
follow to bake such lovely treats. Please note that chocolate is a dog
no-no!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controversy: Real or Fake?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been debated out for an undocumented amount of time: should one
buy real or artificial Christmas trees? Firstly, if you have purchased
an artificial tree, reuse it for a long time to make it
environmentally-friendly. You would have to use it for more than 20
years to make it a more eco-friendly option. Real trees, however, have
surprising benefits to them. Christmas tree farms serve as a habitat for
local wildlife, giving a home to many species. Around 350 million trees
are grown on these farms, with 30 million being harvested. In the
industry continuum, these farms appear on the low end. However, it is
critical to compost or recycle your tree properly. If you’re feeling
extra spicy, offer your tree to mulching and chipping programs, which
help grow more species for one’s garden. To conclude this controversy,
buy a real, locally-grown tree. This also allows you to experience the
process of picking the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/39415781@N06/32470702048&quot;&gt;&quot;Reindeer and sleigh - Orphanage Road,
Erdington&quot;&lt;/a&gt; by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/39415781@N06&quot;&gt;ell brown&lt;/a&gt; is licensed
under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;amp;atype=rich&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC-SA 2.0
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rmatharu</name></author><summary type="html">A guide to tree-ting this season right (filled with history, controversies, and more!)</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2020-02-01-File_4_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Don Cherry Divide</title><link href="/2020/02/The_Don_Cherry_Divide.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Don Cherry Divide" /><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/02/The_Don_Cherry_Divide</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/02/The_Don_Cherry_Divide.html">&lt;p&gt;The winter holidays are a time to embrace the spirit of togetherness, be
merry, and spend time with family. Unfortunately, something happened in
November that has quickly become one of the most heated issues in Canada
(and could lead to awkward conversations with the extended family around
the dinner table). This event was the firing of Don Cherry. You’ve
probably heard about this, but in case you haven’t, here is a brief
rundown of what happened. On Remembrance Day, the 85-year-old NHL
commentator went after immigrants in Toronto and Mississauga, accusing
them of not wearing poppies and not honouring Canada’s veterans.
Undoubtedly the part that drew the most criticism was his use of the
words “you people.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The statement quickly drew widespread criticism, and Sportsnet fired Don
Cherry. Don Cherry, throughout his history as a broadcaster, has had a
history of making very controversial statements. These instances include
the time when he complained about “wom[e]n yapping away” at hockey
games or when he said vulgar things about Liberals at the 2010 inaugural
meeting of Toronto’s new city council, describing the Liberal media as
“left-wing pinkos”, and “kooks”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that may have contributed to Cherry’s firing was his
unwillingness to apologize. In an interview he did with Fox News, he
said that he might have used different wording if he could have done it
over, but came nowhere near giving a formal apology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only were Cherry’s comments offensive, but they were inaccurate and
counterproductive. While the sentiment of getting people to appreciate
all that our veterans have sacrificed for Canada is good, Cherry failed
to take into account that immigrants are also part of the Canadian
military. Sergeant Stephen Thomas, 37, is a first-generation Canadian
with parents from Guyana, who served two tours in Afghanistan, and was
shocked by Cherry’s comments. He said: “I don’t think he’s realized how
much the military has changed over the last decade or two.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason Don Cherry was fired was that his comments, whether
intentional or unintentional (as his supporters claim), hurt people. His
racist, sexist, and rude comments throughout the years may have been few
and far between, but the fact that he was unwilling to apologize says a
lot about his character. His firing is a stepping stone in slowly
getting rid of the voices of discrimination better left in the past. On
this holiday, in the spirit of togetherness, we should all recognize
what Cherry could not - that no matter what country we were born in, we
are all Canadian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.behance.net/gallery/3455711/Hockey-Night-in-Canada&quot;&gt;&quot;Hockey Night in
Canada&quot;&lt;/a&gt;
by Franco Barroeta is licensed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;amp;atype=rich&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC-ND 4.0
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>mhutzul</name></author><summary type="html">The winter holidays are a time to embrace the spirit of togetherness, be merry, and spend time with family. Unfortunately, something happened in November that has quickly become one of the most heated issues in Canada (and could lead to awkward conversations with the extended family around the dinner table). This event was the firing of Don Cherry. You’ve probably heard about this, but in case you haven’t, here is a brief rundown of what happened. On Remembrance Day, the 85-year-old NHL commentator went after immigrants in Toronto and Mississauga, accusing them of not wearing poppies and not honouring Canada’s veterans. Undoubtedly the part that drew the most criticism was his use of the words “you people.”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2020-02-01-The_Don_Cherry_Divide_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Winter Wonderland</title><link href="/2019/12/A_Winter_Wonderland_-_Nicole_Yotis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Winter Wonderland" /><published>2019-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2019/12/A_Winter_Wonderland_-_Nicole_Yotis</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/12/A_Winter_Wonderland_-_Nicole_Yotis.html">&lt;p&gt;Winter is my favourite season, without a doubt. The snow makes
everything look so picturesque and the break is right on our doorstep.
However, for some people, the holidays are dull, with no school to
occupy their days, and friends gone on vacations. But fear not, there
are still so many things to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anything snow-related:&lt;/strong&gt; Take advantage of the season and get out
there. Build a snowman, go sledding or skating, or have a snowball
fight. Winter is also the time to ski, or try something more
outlandish, like ice fishing or snow sculpting. One of my favourite
things to do is build a snow fort with my friends. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indoor activities:&lt;/strong&gt; However fun it is to play in the snow, it’s
cold. But inside, you can make crafts (a great gift idea), catch up
on your reading, draw (the snowy landscape will provide lots of
inspiration), or learn to cook something new. Also, drink hot
chocolate, especially after playing in the snow (that’s the best
time to drink it).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go to a concert:&lt;/strong&gt; There are lots of concerts in December, many
with holiday themes. So whether you’d like to go see your favourite
artist, or maybe go somewhere new, there will definitely be
something to peak your interest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Catch up with old friends:&lt;/strong&gt; I have many friends from elementary
school who I haven’t seen in a long time. The break is a great time
to reach out and plan a time to get together. And if you don’t know
what to do when you see them, perhaps you should try something from
this list. Happy holidays!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/90173772@N00/4215323902&quot;&gt;&quot;Merry
Christmas!&quot;&lt;/a&gt; by xymox is
licensed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;amp;atype=rich&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC-ND
2.0 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nyotis</name></author><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html">Winter is my favourite season, without a doubt. The snow makes everything look so picturesque and the break is right on our doorstep. However, for some people, the holidays are dull, with no school to occupy their days, and friends gone on vacations. But fear not, there are still so many things to do.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2019-12-22-A_Winter_Wonderland_-_Nicole_Yotis_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Grinch Was the Victim</title><link href="/2019/12/The_Grinch_Was_the_Victim_-_Ambika_Mehta.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Grinch Was the Victim" /><published>2019-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2019/12/The_Grinch_Was_the_Victim_-_Ambika_Mehta</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/12/The_Grinch_Was_the_Victim_-_Ambika_Mehta.html">&lt;p&gt;When the Grinch was just a baby&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was left rejected and dangling from a tree&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While he watched the people of WHOville&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attend the annual Christmas party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resilient of the traumatizing events&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Grinch continued his life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until he met Martha May&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And hoped to one day, make her his wife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the Grinch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an outcast in society,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He decided to gather up his courage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And pursue Martha wholeheartedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoping that Martha would see past his rich&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;green skin and hair aplenty,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had an idea that brought him nothing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what felt like notoriety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poor Grinch stayed up all night creating&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The perfect gift for Martha, a girl he adored,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But was made fun of by Augustus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MayWHO, who’s irrelevant entity needed to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;be ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Grinch cut his face when he tried&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;shaving his hair&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when he returned to school&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was surrounded by laughter everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I hate Christmas, I HaTe It!” the Grinch would say,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But he failed to realize that the people of WHOville were phonies
anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They made the Grinch feel unwanted and were materialistic fools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their hearts were small and were straight up cruel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He isolated himself from the people of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WHOville and went to live on top of Mount Crumpit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was accompanied by his dog, Max&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who was always there for him, lickety split&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Grinch’s heart went from big to small in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a matter of time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He grew older and became sour as lime&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had a plan to wreck Christmas for everyone in the town&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But WHO could blame him, the Grinch was a genius, and deserved a crown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was one thing that needed to be served, and that was justice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particularly from the snotty bully named Augustus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Augustus became the mayor of the small town,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But little did he know it was all going &lt;em&gt;doowwn&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fastforward, the mayor proposed to Martha in front of the Grinch,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it wasn't until Martha said “My heart belongs to someone else”,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;that the Grinch’s heart grew more than an inch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion the people of WHOville suck&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the Grinch has nice lashes. The End.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/66478195@N00/6541151793&quot;&gt;&quot;Meeting the
Grinch&quot;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/66478195@N00&quot;&gt;Castles,
Capes &amp;amp; Clones&lt;/a&gt; is licensed
under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;amp;atype=rich&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC-ND
2.0 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>amehta</name></author><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html">When the Grinch was just a baby</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2019-12-22-The_Grinch_Was_the_Victim_-_Ambika_Mehta_photo.jpg" /></entry></feed>