<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-12T21:49:42-05:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Beacon</title><subtitle>The Beacon is Martingrove's newspaper.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A Time to be Empowered</title><link href="/2019/11/November__A_Time_to_be_Empowered.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Time to be Empowered" /><published>2019-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2019/11/November__A_Time_to_be_Empowered</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/11/November__A_Time_to_be_Empowered.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November: A Time to be Empowered&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rhea Matharu&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grade 11 Copy Editor &amp;amp; Production Head&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe, in order to be empowered to take action about this unrevealed
(for now) issue, you will need to be in a different perspective. Close
your eyes and read the following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You begin as a piece of cheap fabric that required 2700 litres of water
(an average person drinks this in 2.5 years). The workers are tired,
struggling with scars on their hands, to piece you together for a living
wage. However, you are only &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;many&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;em&gt;About&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;140 billion
garments&lt;/strong&gt; *are manufactured each year. The amount of resources spent on
you account for nothing as you have a short lifespan. Your impact? You
produced 1.2 billion tonnes of CO2 (per year), yet end up in a landfill
producing more methane. *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This horrifying perspective effectively portrays the product life cycle
that a fast fashion piece of garment experiences. This exposes the
perceived benefit of $20 jeans that last for a very short amount of
time due to its cheap materials. This short lifespan is largely because
of brands like Forever21, Zara, and H&amp;amp;M wanting to match the growing
demand for new, trendy clothing, resulting in new clothing designs and
styles being created every few weeks! Instead of two season cycles,
there are at least 52 seasons for clothing in the fast fashion industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have learned about the harms of the fashion industry, learn
about what you, the consumer, can do to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduce the amount of clothing you buy from fast fashion stores, or
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;even better, stop shopping there altogether. Shop from thrift
stores or stores that sustainably produce their items. The
decreasing demand is sure to change their manufacturing processes.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instead of throwing out your clothing, donate it to stores that
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;accept them or your friends/family. Before buying your clothes,
make sure you know that you will wear it a significant amount of
times.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Reach out to these fast fashion brands to express your concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spread awareness to people you know to expose the hidden truths
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;behind these companies.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This November, empower yourself and others to create less carbon
emissions. The fast fashion industry is one of the largest contributors,
if not the largest, to climate change. Surprisingly, it is not one that
people think of. It’s harm on the planet and terrible working conditions
in factories must be put to an end.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rmatharu</name></author><summary type="html">November: A Time to be Empowered</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2019-11-12-November__A_Time_to_be_Empowered_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Advice on Mornings</title><link href="/2019/11/Advice_on_Mornings_by_April_Naing_1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advice on Mornings" /><published>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2019/11/Advice_on_Mornings_by_April_Naing_1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/11/Advice_on_Mornings_by_April_Naing_1.html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s face it. Most of us aren’t morning people, and with school
starting again a lot of us aren’t used to waking up at the crack of
dawn. Gone are the days when we could sleep until noon and constantly
press “snooze”. However mornings aren’t the worst! In fact, they can
actually be quite nice. They’re quiet and peaceful. The air seems
fresher and catching a sunrise is always a welcome sight. You might even
have a bit of time to be productive! So without further ado, here are
some tips so you can maximize your mornings!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go to sleep earlier!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is pretty straightforward. You need adequate sleep to maintain
your health and sanity! What if you have an assignment? Try sleeping
earlier and then waking up earlier to finish it before school starts.
Help your circadian rhythm by sticking to a regular sleep schedule
including on weekends!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting/choosing an alarm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, annoying alarms will get you up but it’ll also put you in a bad
mood to start your morning. It’ll leave you feeling murderous. Talk
about waking up on the wrong side of your bed...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wake up earlier than you normally do&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that when my alarm goes off getting up is crucial. Lingering
under your covers might be tempting but it also makes you feel more
sluggish and loses precious time for your body to get used to being
awake before you’re off to class. Force yourself to get out of bed!
It’ll depend on each person but 6am-7am is a good time to wake up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open your curtains!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural lighting = very good. Crack open your window for fresh air and
to hear the birds chirp!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Put on some music!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music can set up the atmosphere and instantly improve your mood in the
morning! You could play your favorite jam to get you pumped up or a nice
soundtrack for a calming and happy effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water is your best friend&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your body hasn’t had any water for hours by now! Down a glass of fresh
H₂O to rehydrate and splash your face with cold water to get refreshed.
You can opt for a quick shower too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breakfast isn’t negotiable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re like me you’re probably guilty of skipping this vital part of
your mornings. A healthy breakfast improves your memory and mood and
helps you stay concentrated. It’s key for productivity. Recently I’ve
leaned towards a small bowl of cereal or toast, some fruit and a cup of
green tea or coffee!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people may find a walk or run in the morning really helps
especially in the morning when the air feels fresher. Or just brave an
ice cold shower and get a mini heart attack. A warm shower might just
make your drowsier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan your day!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to a good end is a good start! Jot down a to-do list in your
bullet journal, agenda, phone or just think about it on your commute.
Alternatively you can have a morning journal to write your thoughts or
keep track of your dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BONUS (Apps to try out!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sleepyti.me:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a sleep calculator that really works! You’ll
feel more refreshed in the day if you don’t wake up in the middle of a
sleep cycle. Sleepyti.me helps you to wake up at the optimal time so
that you don’t interrupt any cycles!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WhiteNoise:&lt;/strong&gt; WhiteNoise is a free app that gives you a ton of tracks
and calming sounds to choose from that will play from your phone to help
you sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pacifica:&lt;/strong&gt; This one is for if you’re feeling stressed or anxious.
Includes trackers and exercises to try. You can also use it to talk to
others who are feeling the same stress. It’s a free app too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image via Flickr&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>anaing</name></author><summary type="html">Let’s face it. Most of us aren’t morning people, and with school starting again a lot of us aren’t used to waking up at the crack of dawn. Gone are the days when we could sleep until noon and constantly press “snooze”. However mornings aren’t the worst! In fact, they can actually be quite nice. They’re quiet and peaceful. The air seems fresher and catching a sunrise is always a welcome sight. You might even have a bit of time to be productive! So without further ado, here are some tips so you can maximize your mornings!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2019-11-10-Advice_on_Mornings_by_April_Naing_1_photo.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lest We Forget</title><link href="/2019/11/April_Naing_-_Remembrance_Day-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lest We Forget" /><published>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2019/11/April_Naing_-_Remembrance_Day-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/11/April_Naing_-_Remembrance_Day-2.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remembrance Day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remembrance Day &lt;em&gt;(Jour du Souvenir)&lt;/em&gt; is observed annually on November
11, the anniversary marking the end of World War 1. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The First World War was the largest conflict the world had ever seen at
the time. The war was a result of many factors, including political
tension and military alliances. The assassination of Archduke Franz
Ferdinand of Austria in 1914 sparked the beginning of a crisis and the
war began that same year in August. It would become a bloody four year
war with close to 61,000 Canadians killed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally the day was called “Armistice Day” to commemorate the
armistice agreement which ended the war on Monday, November 11, 1918, at
11 a.m, the eleventh hour of the eleventh day of the eleventh month. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vimy Ridge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considered Canada’s most celebrated Canadian military victory, the
battle of Vimy Ridge was fought from the 9th to 12th of April 1917 on
the Western Front of northern France. Four divisions of the Canadian
Corps fought united and captured the ridge from the German army. It was
the largest territorial advance of any Allied force at that point in the
war. Unfortunately the cost of the victory was overwhelming; more than
10,600 Canadians were killed or wounded in the battle. Today a memorial
stands at the top of the ridge to honour the 11,285 Canadians killed in
France throughout the war who have no marked graves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remembering &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day serves to remember all the lives that were lost in the line of
duty and the countless sacrifices soldiers made to uphold international
peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically there is a National Ceremony on the date each year at the
National War Memorial in Ottawa. It is nationally televised and attended
by the Prime Minister, government officials, veterans organizations’
representatives, diplomatic representatives, dignitaries, veterans as
well as the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Can You Do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•Remember those who served and the fallen. Honour their sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•Have a respectful moment of silence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•Wear the Remembrance Day symbol, a poppy, with the &lt;em&gt;correct etiquette&lt;/em&gt;,
that is: on the left over your heart, from the last Friday in October
until November 11&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/34534185@N00/48685673082&quot;&gt;&quot;Remembrance Day
Poppy_2=&quot;&lt;/a&gt; by Sheba_Also
46000 + photos-Videos is licensed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;amp;atype=rich&quot;&gt;CC BY-SA
2.0 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>anaing</name></author><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html">Remembrance Day</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2019-11-10-April_Naing_-_Remembrance_Day-2_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How Independent Are You? A Quiz for Young Adults Who Think They’re Ready To Be Adults</title><link href="/2019/11/Independent.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Independent Are You? A Quiz for Young Adults Who Think They’re Ready To Be Adults" /><published>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2019/11/Independent</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/11/Independent.html">&lt;p&gt;For several years, we, the students of MCI, have had, for the most part,
a simple structure to our lives. Wake up. Go to school. Eat. Sleep.
Climb a level in the education system (ideally) annually. Spend your
free time as you like it. This is the regular childhood and adolescence
of most suburban youth. We are extraordinarily lucky to be living in a
time and place that allows us to mature in such a slow, gentle manner.
But like it or not, time is taking us closer to adulthood, buckaroos.
Whether it’s dragging you, by the hair, or softly carrying you, we all
have the same destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And let’s face it, some of us are more ready to become “functioning
members of society” than others. Are you one of them? Let’s see how many
bears are ready to tackle the hardships of a grown-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This quiz is, of course, purely for fun. Don’t bother to cheat or look
up anything. Save your calories for a math test. Answers are at the end!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Ideally&lt;/em&gt;, you should be putting at least __ of your earnings
aside as savings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  5% &lt;strong&gt;b)&lt;/strong&gt; 10% &lt;strong&gt;c)&lt;/strong&gt; 15% &lt;strong&gt;d)&lt;/strong&gt; 20% &lt;strong&gt;e)&lt;/strong&gt; 30%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; While deep frying french fries, some oil spills on the gas
stovetop and catches fire. Both your countertop and the pot of oil are
on fire! What is the best way (aside from using a fire extinguisher) to
put it out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Pour a deep bowl of water on all the flames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b)  Turn off the heat and smother fires with metal (a metal pot lid,
    &amp;gt; baking sheet, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c)  Move the pot outside, spray water on the countertop and call 911.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;d)  Sprinkle a little baking soda on the fires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Which of the following is NOT at all covered by OHIP?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Emergency healthcare &lt;strong&gt;b)&lt;/strong&gt; Casts and crutches&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c)&lt;/strong&gt; Dental surgeries (in a hospital) &lt;strong&gt;d)&lt;/strong&gt; Hospital stays&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; What does GIC stand for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Guaranteed Investment Certificate &lt;strong&gt;b)&lt;/strong&gt; The newest Kpop group&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c)&lt;/strong&gt; Generalized Intensive Care &lt;strong&gt;d)&lt;/strong&gt; Green Innovation Committee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt; What is the first tool to reach for when your toilet is clogged?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  cup plunger &lt;strong&gt;b)&lt;/strong&gt; flange plunger&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c)&lt;/strong&gt; toilet brush &lt;strong&gt;d)&lt;/strong&gt; a wire clothing hanger from Walmart&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.&lt;/strong&gt; Which of these should NOT be stored in the fridge?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Raw zucchini &lt;strong&gt;b)&lt;/strong&gt; Whole, unpeeled onions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c)&lt;/strong&gt; Green beans &lt;strong&gt;d)&lt;/strong&gt; Cut portobello mushrooms&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.&lt;/strong&gt; The best stitch for strength and security (and mending clothes)
is the _______.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Straight stitch &lt;strong&gt;b)&lt;/strong&gt; Backstitch &lt;strong&gt;c)&lt;/strong&gt; Running stitch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;d)&lt;/strong&gt; Hidden stitch &lt;strong&gt;e)&lt;/strong&gt; Cross stitch &lt;strong&gt;f)&lt;/strong&gt; Whip stitch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.&lt;/strong&gt; How often is it recommended that you clean/change your bedding?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Every 1-2 weeks &lt;strong&gt;b)&lt;/strong&gt; Every month&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c)&lt;/strong&gt; Every 2 months &lt;strong&gt;d)&lt;/strong&gt; It doesn’t matter, as long as it looks
clean and doesn’t smell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9.&lt;/strong&gt; When is electricity the cheapest in Ontario?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Before 7 am and after 7 pm, weekdays&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b)  11 am to 5 pm, weekdays&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c)  Weekends and holidays&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;d)  Electricity is the same price at any time of the day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;e)  Both a and c&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10.&lt;/strong&gt; Who can ask you for your SIN (Social Insurance Number)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Your college/university admissions office&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b)  Your landlord, negotiating a lease with you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c)  Your (confirmed) employer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;d)  No one but the government&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all I have for you now! Hopefully you did well. If not, don’t
worry-you still have time to learn. Most people pick this kind of stuff
up as they go, anyway. Though this couldn’t have gone too badly. I
didn’t even put any questions on doing taxes. Maybe next issue~?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Answers: **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.(d) 2.(b) 3.(b) 4.(a) 5.(b) 6.(b) 7.(b) 8.(a) 9.(e) 10.(c)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image via Shutterstock&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>lli</name></author><summary type="html">For several years, we, the students of MCI, have had, for the most part, a simple structure to our lives. Wake up. Go to school. Eat. Sleep. Climb a level in the education system (ideally) annually. Spend your free time as you like it. This is the regular childhood and adolescence of most suburban youth. We are extraordinarily lucky to be living in a time and place that allows us to mature in such a slow, gentle manner. But like it or not, time is taking us closer to adulthood, buckaroos. Whether it’s dragging you, by the hair, or softly carrying you, we all have the same destination.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2019-11-10-Independent_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Reasoning Behind Spider-Man’s Exit from the MCU</title><link href="/2019/11/Sanaa_Mahmud_-_Spidermans_Exit_from_the_MCU.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Reasoning Behind Spider-Man’s Exit from the MCU" /><published>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2019/11/Sanaa_Mahmud_-_Spidermans_Exit_from_the_MCU</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/11/Sanaa_Mahmud_-_Spidermans_Exit_from_the_MCU.html">&lt;p&gt;If you’re a Marvel fan like me, then you’ve probably heard about the
recent drama between Sony and Disney regarding Spider-Man. If you
haven’t heard about what is happening, here’s a summary. Sony has owned
the film rights to Spider-Man since 1998. In 2015, they made a deal with
Disney, agreeing to lend the character of Spider-Man to Marvel Studios,
a company owned by Disney, and to the Marvel Cinematic Universe. As we
have seen over the last few years, Tom Holland’s Spider Man has played a
large role in many Marvel movies. Recently, Sony and Disney have
revisited their deal, and gone through negotiations about future steps
for the Spider-Man character. On August 20th, 2019, Sony announced that
Kevin Feige, president of Marvel Studios, won’t be playing a role in the
production of the next Spider-Man film. This means that Spider-Man is
currently not a part of the MCU anymore. This news left fans feeling
both angry and heartbroken, since Marvel’s latest movie, “Spider-Man:
Far From Home” had set up Spider-Man to be the new face of the
franchise. Upon hearing about this, I didn’t understand what happened
between the two major companies, and wanted to know the reason behind
the decisions being made. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sony owns the rights to Spider-Man and gets to keep them as long as they
make a new Spider-Man movie every five to six years. They started with
“Spider-Man” in 2002, starring Tobey Maguire. After its success, they
proceeded to release “Spider-Man 2”, and then “Spider-Man 3” in 2007.
The third movie didn’t do quite as well as hoped, costing $260 million
to make, with profits dipping significantly from the first two movies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five years later, Sony decided to reboot the series, and released “The
Amazing Spider-Man” starring Andrew Garfield. This movie made over $700
million worldwide. With its success,”The Amazing Spider-Man 2” was made.
Unfortunately, it did not live up to Sony’s expectations, with the very
high production costs and lessened excitement from fans. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of their failed attempts, Sony struck a deal with Disney in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marvel would be able to use Spider-Man in their cinematic
universe, while Sony kept distribution rights and creative control. Sony
producer, Amy Pascal, who played a big role in the creation of the
Spider-Man movies since 2002, produced &quot;Spider-Man: Homecoming&quot; and
&quot;Spider-Man: Far From Home&quot; with Kevin Feige. This deal had been
upheld by both sides, until Sony decided to revisit the idea of making
their own Spider-Man films. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Sony has been doing well with their own ‘Universe of Marvel
Characters’. “Venom” made over $800 million worldwide after being
released in 2018, and “Spider-Man: Far From Home” made over $1 billion
this summer. These successes have been “just the rebound Sony needed.”
Spider-Man is Sony’s greatest property, and they are highly motivated to
keep it in their control.. This is why they had such an interest in
taking back the character. Another reason why the deal was being
revisited was because Disney wanted a 50/50 stake in future
&quot;Spider-Man&quot; movies. Sony wanted to keep the deal as is: where Marvel
receives up to 5% of first-dollar gross and all merchandising revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of right now, no new deal has been made. This indicates that unless
something changes, Marvel Studios will not be involved in the making of
new Spider-Man movies, and no MCU characters will be referenced. Sony
hopes that Director John Watts and star Tom Holland will return for two
more Spider-Man films. Even though this feels like a big loss for fans,
we should remember that there are still more movies being made, and even
though Marvel seems to be out of Spider-Man's life right now, Sony is
hopeful that a deal could still be made in the future. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Note: This article was written before the agreement between Sony and
Disney to keep Spiderman in the MCU was reached.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>smahmud</name></author><summary type="html">If you’re a Marvel fan like me, then you’ve probably heard about the recent drama between Sony and Disney regarding Spider-Man. If you haven’t heard about what is happening, here’s a summary. Sony has owned the film rights to Spider-Man since 1998. In 2015, they made a deal with Disney, agreeing to lend the character of Spider-Man to Marvel Studios, a company owned by Disney, and to the Marvel Cinematic Universe. As we have seen over the last few years, Tom Holland’s Spider Man has played a large role in many Marvel movies. Recently, Sony and Disney have revisited their deal, and gone through negotiations about future steps for the Spider-Man character. On August 20th, 2019, Sony announced that Kevin Feige, president of Marvel Studios, won’t be playing a role in the production of the next Spider-Man film. This means that Spider-Man is currently not a part of the MCU anymore. This news left fans feeling both angry and heartbroken, since Marvel’s latest movie, “Spider-Man: Far From Home” had set up Spider-Man to be the new face of the franchise. Upon hearing about this, I didn’t understand what happened between the two major companies, and wanted to know the reason behind the decisions being made. </summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Whoop whoop announcement test</title><link href="/2019/05/test-announcement.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Whoop whoop announcement test" /><published>2019-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2019/05/test-announcement</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/05/test-announcement.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello irrybodie.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>srao</name></author><summary type="html">Hello irrybodie.</summary></entry></feed>