<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-07T22:52:32+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Beacon</title><subtitle>The Beacon is MCI's newspaper.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Leadership Issue</title><link href="/2023/10/Leadership_Article.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leadership Issue" /><published>2023-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2023/10/Leadership_Article</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/10/Leadership_Article.html">&lt;p&gt;This month, Grade 10 students went to Camp Manitou up in Parry Sound for
Leadership Camp 2023. They were accompanied by several teachers, staff,
and Grade 11 and 12 students returning as Activity Leaders, Counselors,
and BLT’s (Bears Leadership Team). Campers left school early in the
morning on October 2nd, and (begrudgingly) departed from camp after
eating lunch on October 5th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campers were engaged in numerous activities each day, such as Outdoor
Survival (including shelter building and archery), Camp Rock, Field
Games, Dance, Group Rec (including sports, yoga, and mindfulness), Rocks
&amp;amp; Ropes, Hiking &amp;amp; Geocaching, Drama, Co-op, and Arts and Crafts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evenings, students of all color groups would partake in
activities, including Camp-Wide Games (a series of minigames in which
color groups would compete for the most points), Color Chaos (a
collection of games played by all campers in the camp’s hangar), and on
the last day, a Talent Show and a Dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, two new color groups joined the roster of the traditional
colors of the rainbow: pink and silver. The winner of the Rocks &amp;amp; Ropes
Participation trophy, a trophy recognizing the team that was most
engaged and immersed during the activity, was Team Pink. However, Team
Orange won both the Archery contest and Camp-Wide Games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We collectively would like to thank Mr. Hartill for supporting us and
the organization of this camp. After 15 years of dedication, care, and
hard work for Leadership Camp, Mr. Hartill will be leaving the program
for his retirement - he will be missed! Without his contributions and
efforts, Leadership Camp would not have been the magical experience it
is and has been for so many Martingrove students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attendees of Leadership Camp can look forward to the reunion breakfast
taking place during the late start on Wednesday, November 29th. A list
of resources/contacts that students are able to access if they are in
need of help (or just someone to talk to) is available on the Leadership
Camp Instagram page, found with the user “@mcileadership”. Remember we
are all here to support each other!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dpatel</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html">This month, Grade 10 students went to Camp Manitou up in Parry Sound for Leadership Camp 2023. They were accompanied by several teachers, staff, and Grade 11 and 12 students returning as Activity Leaders, Counselors, and BLT’s (Bears Leadership Team). Campers left school early in the morning on October 2nd, and (begrudgingly) departed from camp after eating lunch on October 5th.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2023-10-29-Leadership-Camp-2023.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/2023-10-29-Leadership-Camp-2023.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Goospocalypse</title><link href="/2023/10/Goospocalypse.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goospocalypse" /><published>2023-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2023/10/Goospocalypse</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/10/Goospocalypse.html">&lt;p&gt;To many people, geese are probably the “Karens” of the animal kingdom—
constantly inducing fear wherever they go, and honking nonstop. Love ‘em
or hate ‘em, they aren’t going anywhere. So, as payback for all the poop
we’ve had to wipe from the bottoms of our shoes, we might as well gossip
about them behind their backs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of days, I’ve interviewed many people about their
interactions and feelings about geese, and these people have had their
fair share of trauma. Fiona, a Grade 9, says that a goose bit her, and
countless other people I interviewed shared stories about being chased
by geese. One of these people was Nyela, another Grade 9, who says that
a goose attacked her while she was walking peacefully (yikes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But have no fear, because for those of you who love geese, there is a
small but still-existing hope for their public image. While it’s not a
gold star of approval, the feelings these people have for them is not
hate. Some people have come forward saying that they feel apathetic
towards geese, and on rare occasions, the student body has even seen the
geese being friendly with a mysterious student from our school, dubbed
the “goose whisperer”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see for myself if the overwhelming hate for geese at our school was
unfounded or not, I went to the front of the school, one of the places
where a lot of the geese spend their time, and attempted to interview a
whole gaggle of them. My attempt was unsuccessful, though, because, for
some reason, no matter how close I stalked behind them and made noise, I
was practically invisible to them. So for now, I guess I must go on, not
knowing why they insist on harassing our wonderful MCI students!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, no matter the opinion you may have of geese, whether it’s the
urge to burn them to the ground or the longing to play house with them,
they’re not showing any sign of leaving anytime soon, so we might as
well accept it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish you many years of not coming into contact with goose poop! Honk
you later!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>cemeka</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html">To many people, geese are probably the “Karens” of the animal kingdom— constantly inducing fear wherever they go, and honking nonstop. Love ‘em or hate ‘em, they aren’t going anywhere. So, as payback for all the poop we’ve had to wipe from the bottoms of our shoes, we might as well gossip about them behind their backs.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2023-10-24-Goospocalypse.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/2023-10-24-Goospocalypse.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How old is too old for halloween?</title><link href="/2023/10/TooOldHalloween.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How old is too old for halloween?" /><published>2023-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2023/10/TooOldHalloween</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/10/TooOldHalloween.html">&lt;p&gt;Every year, millions of young Canadians celebrate Halloween by dressing
up, going around the neighbourhood, and collecting candy that will stay
in their cupboards for the weeks to come. Although Halloween is a staple
in nearly every person’s childhood, there comes a point when they have
to ditch the festivities and stop trick-or-treating for good. Sadly,
after this Halloween, some of us may be approaching that point, so we
must ask ourselves that looming question: How old is too old to
trick-or-treat?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The greatest reason for trick-or-treating is how fun it is. When we’re
young, we’re excited by the candy and being able to dress up as our
favourite characters. As we get older, maybe we’ve simply already
experienced everything Halloween can offer us. The mystique is lost and
we end up looking for new activities to spice up the season. On the
other hand, some people believe trick-or-treating is exclusively for
little kids, and pressure older children to stop. There’s also many kids
who just get tired of going out, and would rather stay home and watch
horror movies. There’s a wide array of reasons why people stop
participating in Halloween, but none of them answer the question at
hand: What is the age when it all ends?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although a lot about this topic is up for debate, it’s an unwritten rule
that Halloween isn’t for adults. Most people believe the unofficial
cutoff should be around 14 or 15 years old, when people have already
become accustomed to the high schooler lifestyle and can comfortably
call themselves adolescents. At that age, they are no longer considered
children and have to adapt to more responsibilities, which can imply
ditching activities deemed ‘for kids’. Others say the official cutoff
should be when people become ‘official adults’ at 18. If you’re still
considered a kid by the government, then why not consider yourself young
enough to participate in Halloween? Although this is all technically
true, another stark reality is that most adults don’t appreciate giving
out candy to the older kids on Halloween. Most parents and adults
encourage the 14-15 cutoff, which is why it’s widely recognized as the
prime time to stop and begin looking for other ways to spend the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though there’s no definitive age when people should drop
trick-or-treating, we can all agree that by the time we start high
school, we should start looking at other ways to spend Halloween.
There’s so much that the holiday offers, and so many different ways to
spend it: watch a scary movie, go to a seriously haunted castle, devise
innovative ways to scare your younger siblings (my personal favourite!),
etc. Of course, if going trick-or-treating with friends or family still
sounds like the best option, go for it!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>lcousins</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html">Every year, millions of young Canadians celebrate Halloween by dressing up, going around the neighbourhood, and collecting candy that will stay in their cupboards for the weeks to come. Although Halloween is a staple in nearly every person’s childhood, there comes a point when they have to ditch the festivities and stop trick-or-treating for good. Sadly, after this Halloween, some of us may be approaching that point, so we must ask ourselves that looming question: How old is too old to trick-or-treat?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2023-10-24-How-Old-Is-Too-Old-For-Halloween.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/2023-10-24-How-Old-Is-Too-Old-For-Halloween.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Atomic Blonde: My night with Barbenheimer</title><link href="/2023/10/Barbenheimer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Atomic Blonde: My night with Barbenheimer" /><published>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2023/10/Barbenheimer</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/10/Barbenheimer.html">&lt;p&gt;She’s everything. He’s just Death, the “destroyer of worlds”. Do they
need any other introduction? Barbenheimer, Atomic Blonde, whatever you
want to call it, there was an undeniably explosive impact when &lt;em&gt;Barbie&lt;/em&gt;
and &lt;em&gt;Oppenheimer&lt;/em&gt; were unleashed upon theaters this summer. As a
cultural moment, it spawned double features, fashion trends, and
countless memes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even before their release dates, &lt;em&gt;Barbie&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Oppenheimer&lt;/em&gt; were
consistently in the news, including sparking controversy over maps of
the South China Sea, creating discussions about the gender wage gap when
casting actors, and even causing a worldwide shortage of pink paint. On
the surface, it seems like the question to be asking is, ‘Why
Barbenheimer?’. Why these two movies now? They weren’t two sides of a
war moving towards mutually assured destruction. Instead, the public
decided that they were perfectly matched partners, dancing the night
away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, Barbenheimer is more than just the atomic wasteland next
to the Dreamhouse. Both movies deal with the existential themes that are
created by the implications of a world changing invasion. Both movies
are passion projects from well-respected writer-directors with clear,
recognizable styles. Both movies have an amazing set and wardrobe, and
expansive star-studded casts. Most importantly, both movies have this
living, breathing passion behind them for filmmaking as a craft, and
this can be felt in every second of both the movies. So, the real
question I propose we ask instead is, ‘What does Barbenheimer mean to
us?’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I know what Barbenheimer means to me. Hands down, it was one of
the best movie watching experiences I’ve had this year! I usually watch
movies in one of two ways: by myself in the dark, or—if it’s a real
masterpiece like &lt;em&gt;Castle Freak&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Space Truckers—&lt;/em&gt;by myself in the
dark, yelling at the screen, and laughing at my own jokes. In reality,
going to the theater with my friends to see Barbenheimer this summer was
incredibly special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So on game day, I suited up in my best pink threads and marched towards
the nearly 6-hour-long behemoth I was about to tackle. My friends and I
started with &lt;em&gt;Oppenheimer&lt;/em&gt;, a tactical decision made because, by all
accounts, no one wanted to leave the fun hangout with friends on a sour
note (pondering the horrors of war). As soon as the movie started I was
hit with two realizations: one, this was going to be a brilliant movie
and two, this was the most &lt;em&gt;Nolan&lt;/em&gt; that Christopher Nolan the
writer/director has ever Nolaned. By that I mean it has gripping sound
design, beautiful shots with natural lighting, timeline confusion,
famous or upcoming actors in glorified cameos (Shout-out to Jack Quaid
and his bongos) and Cillian Murphy in incredibly well-cut suits. If you
put this movie in a line-up of other releases this year and said ‘pick
out the Nolan movie’, it would be like putting Michael Myers in a police
line-up and saying ‘pick out the killer’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After taking a break to refuel, we were met with waves of pink flooding
the lobby of the theater. Everyone was fully dressed to the nines to see
one movie: &lt;em&gt;Barbie&lt;/em&gt;. Getting into the theater and seeing all the
female-presenting people waiting to watch the movie gave me a flashback
to the last time I was in a similar situation. In middle school, all the
girls in my class were taken to the gym to watch a documentary about
‘female empowerment’, which was just really brutal stories about girls
being catty to each other. When we got back, we found out that the boys
had gotten to spend the entire period playing video games. &lt;em&gt;Barbie&lt;/em&gt;
takes this viewpoint and promptly kicks it out of the Dreamhouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it the perfect movie on feminism? No. &lt;em&gt;Barbie&lt;/em&gt; is like Bernie Sanders
running in an election. It’s there to start a conversation. Despite the
immaculate sets, perfect costume designs, and brilliant wielding of
Mattel Lore (I see you, Magic Earring Ken), the part of &lt;em&gt;Barbie&lt;/em&gt; that I
enjoyed the most was the positive atmosphere in the theater. There were
so many different people watching and enjoying the movie. When America
Ferrera gave a speech about how hard it is to be a woman, the entire
theater started clapping- something I’ve never ever experienced before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m worried that movie execs will take the wrong message from
Barbenheimer. Studios are already trying to replicate this success by
releasing the horror film &lt;em&gt;Saw 10&lt;/em&gt; and the children’s film &lt;em&gt;Paw Patrol,&lt;/em&gt;
and marketing them as ‘Saw Patrol’. But what they fail to understand is
that you can’t force meaning into movies - the truth is, people make the
movies meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>awong</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html">She’s everything. He’s just Death, the “destroyer of worlds”. Do they need any other introduction? Barbenheimer, Atomic Blonde, whatever you want to call it, there was an undeniably explosive impact when Barbie and Oppenheimer were unleashed upon theaters this summer. As a cultural moment, it spawned double features, fashion trends, and countless memes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2023-10-23-Atomic-Blonde-My-Night-With-Barbenheimer.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/2023-10-23-Atomic-Blonde-My-Night-With-Barbenheimer.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Modern Dystopia Censoring News Across the Nation</title><link href="/2023/10/Bill_C1984.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Modern Dystopia Censoring News Across the Nation" /><published>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2023/10/Bill_C1984</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/10/Bill_C1984.html">&lt;p&gt;In June 2023, the federal government passed Bill C-18, &lt;em&gt;An Act
respecting online communications platforms that make news content
available to persons in Canada—&lt;/em&gt;otherwise known as the Online News Act.
You might have noticed the response to this legislation on Instagram—
over the summer, every single reputed news source was blocked on Meta’s
platforms, like Instagram and Facebook, and the block remains today.
Currently, if a Canadian Instagram user tries to search for any
reputable media company on the app, they are presented with a blank
screen that reads, “People in Canada can’t see this content”. The
&lt;em&gt;Martingrove Beacon&lt;/em&gt;’s very own Instagram page was even blocked with the
same message earlier this year. Without trusted news sources available
at the tips of Canadians’ fingertips, unverified news and misinformation
can run rampant through Instagram, Facebook, and Threads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Department of Justice, the purpose of Bill C-18 is to
“support news businesses to secure fair compensation when their news
content is made available by dominant digital news intermediaries and
generates economic gain.” In other words, this legislation aims to
ensure that journalists and news companies are paid fairly when their
content is viewed and monetized on outlets that are not directly owned
by those companies, especially in a “market environment that has been
disadvantageous to news businesses.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no news that print media is on a steady decline—according to
Statistics Canada, Canadian newspapers had a 23.9% decrease in print
advertising sales from 2018 to 2020. People aren’t buying newspapers
anymore, especially not our generation. What Gen Z prefers, instead, is
Instagram. Before Instagram’s recent ban, news was widely available on
the app— trusted Canadian and international news organizations would
post their content in a quick, simple format, accessible by all, and
most importantly, &lt;em&gt;free.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CBC News used to post its articles in an easily digestible format on
Instagram, but the power imbalance between the CBC and the $794 billion
technology conglomerate, Meta, meant that the CBC had little control
over how much of the revenue from its Instagram content went into its
pocket, and how much went into Meta’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill C-18, however, aims to strengthen the “bargaining position” of news
businesses in proportion to “large and dominant digital news
intermediaries”, such as Instagram or X (formerly known as Twitter),
essentially making sure that the journalists and other employees at
these news companies are compensated fairly, instead of being bullied
into submission by the platforms that host them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The just thing for these social media platforms to do is to pay the news
companies fairly, so that Canadians still have access to what’s
happening in the world around them, and so that news companies can
survive, at a time when the news industry is on a rapid decline.
However, Meta, the parent company of Instagram and Facebook, had a
different approach. Meta banned news altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canadians have begun to rely on subscriptions and apps from their
favourite news sources, now that they are gone from Instagram. However,
a key demographic is missing from this solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Young Canadians are not subscribing to these newspapers. No teenager is
spending their minimum wage earnings on an online subscription to the
&lt;em&gt;Globe and Mail&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Toronto Star,&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Walrus&lt;/em&gt;. Moreover, it is
impractical for a teenager to take the time out of a busy school day
filled with clubs and extracurriculars to scan the front page of a news
website, or browse through an email newsletter. Meta’s response to Bill
C-18 has also included a ban on sharing links from news sources to
users’ Instagram “stories”, effectively ridding every single channel of
communication for young people of reputable news, in a time where
misinformation is rampant. Without trusted news sources on Instagram,
Canadian youth have been left in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the fundamental freedoms, section 2b of the Charter of Rights and
Freedoms, Canadians are entitled to “freedom of the press and other
media of communication.” If Canadians must follow the law, why can’t
Meta?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sxiang</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html">In June 2023, the federal government passed Bill C-18, An Act respecting online communications platforms that make news content available to persons in Canada—otherwise known as the Online News Act. You might have noticed the response to this legislation on Instagram— over the summer, every single reputed news source was blocked on Meta’s platforms, like Instagram and Facebook, and the block remains today. Currently, if a Canadian Instagram user tries to search for any reputable media company on the app, they are presented with a blank screen that reads, “People in Canada can’t see this content”. The Martingrove Beacon’s very own Instagram page was even blocked with the same message earlier this year. Without trusted news sources available at the tips of Canadians’ fingertips, unverified news and misinformation can run rampant through Instagram, Facebook, and Threads.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Canada qualifies for Paris Olympics 2024</title><link href="/2023/10/OlympicBasketball.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Canada qualifies for Paris Olympics 2024" /><published>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2023/10/OlympicBasketball</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/10/OlympicBasketball.html">&lt;p&gt;The hype was high in the basketball world as OKC Thunder star
Shai-Gilgeous Alexander nailed a free throw to secure Canada’s spot in
the 2024 Paris Olympics. Defeating Spain 88 - 85 in an intense duel,
Canada managed to overcome their years of misery; loss after loss, and
just when hope seemed gone, the team reached international recognition.
For those of you who aren’t into sports like I am, Team Canada clinched
an Olympics berth in basketball for the first time in 23 years! And not
only that, but Canada has only ever won one Olympic medal for
basketball: a silver at the 1936 Berlin Olympics. Accolades aside,
Canada’s road to the 2024 Paris Olympics has been absolutely climactic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canada entered the court with their team and FOUR star players:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shai-Gilgeous Alexander of the Oklahoma City Thunder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dillon Brooks of the Houston Rockets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R.J. Barrett of the New York Knicks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Luguentz Dort of the Oklahoma City Thunder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first round, Canada played against France, and Canada taught them
quite a lesson with a 95 - 65 score, and a stellar performance from
Alexander: 27 points, 13 rebounds and 6 assists! He made it quite close
to the elusive triple double (10 points, 10 rebounds, 10 assists).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canada proceeded to the next games with increased confidence. Sure
enough, they defeated Lebanon 128 - 73, and went on to beat Latvia 101 -
75.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the second round, and we had Canada facing Brazil. Despite
Canada’s boosted confidence and intense preparations, they ultimately
fell to Brazil 65 - 69.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then came the moment we’d all been waiting for: Canada versus Spain.
The Spanish team was the reigning champion from the last FIBA cup, yet
Canada had fostered an excellent record of 3 wins and a loss. With the
ultimate matchup of the champs vs the underdogs, the unprecedented
happened. Canada was up 86 - 85, when Alexander was fouled. Given two
shots, Alexander focused and aimed for history. If Canada won, they’d
qualify for the Paris 2024 Olympics. Whether or not Alexander felt the
pressure, he made both those shots, resulting in Canada’s 88 - 85 lead.
With 4.5 seconds on the clock, the Spanish players zipped across the
court, and when Alex Abrines (Spain) attempted a three-pointer and
missed, it was over. Canada had officially made the Olympics. Both
stars, namely Dillon Brooks and Alexander, had stunning performances:
Alexander with 30 points, 4 rebounds, and 7 assists, while Brooks became
the 3-pointer legend with 22 points, 5 rebounds and 2 assists. Hats off
to both of Team Canada’s heroes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it’s quite a harsh way to say it, having just one medal in the
trophy case gives us a bigger reason to celebrate Canada’s clinch. So
let’s hit the court to watch some of the best basketball Team Canada has
to offer, and some historic performances. Paris doesn’t know what’s
coming for them!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jkhan</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html">The hype was high in the basketball world as OKC Thunder star Shai-Gilgeous Alexander nailed a free throw to secure Canada’s spot in the 2024 Paris Olympics. Defeating Spain 88 - 85 in an intense duel, Canada managed to overcome their years of misery; loss after loss, and just when hope seemed gone, the team reached international recognition. For those of you who aren’t into sports like I am, Team Canada clinched an Olympics berth in basketball for the first time in 23 years! And not only that, but Canada has only ever won one Olympic medal for basketball: a silver at the 1936 Berlin Olympics. Accolades aside, Canada’s road to the 2024 Paris Olympics has been absolutely climactic.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2023-10-23-Canada-qualifies-for-Paris-Olympics-2024.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/2023-10-23-Canada-qualifies-for-Paris-Olympics-2024.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Halloween Interviews with MCI teachers</title><link href="/2023/10/Teacher_Interviews.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Halloween Interviews with MCI teachers" /><published>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2023/10/Teacher_Interviews</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/10/Teacher_Interviews.html">&lt;p&gt;Two weeks before the beloved holiday where people wear elaborate
costumes to scavenge every home in the neighborhood in search of the
best candy possible, I interviewed some of the particularly festive
teachers at MCI. To be specific, I interviewed the following teachers on
their favorite candy and their most memorable Halloween experiences from
when they were younger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ms. Thomson (has taught at MCI for 20 years to date)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location: History Room (which she also was in as a student at MCI)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nadine:&lt;/strong&gt; My first question for you is, what is your preferred
Halloween candy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ms. Thomson:&lt;/strong&gt; Reese’s peanut butter cups. Hands down the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nadine:&lt;/strong&gt; No hesitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ms. Thomson:&lt;/strong&gt; No hesitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nadine:&lt;/strong&gt; An understandable choice. My other question is, what would
you consider your most memorable Halloween experience to be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ms. Thomson:&lt;/strong&gt; One time, when I was trick or treating, I was quite
young then, I went to somebody’s house and I knocked on the door. Then,
the fellow came out, and I had my bag and was in my costume - I don’t
even remember what it was, and I said, “Trick or treat!” He responded,
“Give me a trick and I’ll give you a treat!” and I never heard anyone
say anything like that before. Usually, people just put the candy in
your basket and you walk away, the usual procedure you know? And it
threw me so off guard that I just froze and I just stood there and I
didn’t know what to do. Then, finally, I just walked away. I didn’t even
get any candy, it was just the weirdest experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nadine:&lt;/strong&gt; Did you see his expression after? What was his reaction?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ms. Thomson:&lt;/strong&gt; No, I can’t really remember too much aside from that. I
remember it was a man, an older man, and I think it was like a dad joke
kind of thing where he was just trying to be funny, only I didn’t get it
at first and it threw me so off guard. I was also really nervous so I
just kinda froze. That’s a memorable experience for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nadine:&lt;/strong&gt; Thank you, Ms. Thomson!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mme. Ferland (has also taught at MCI for 20 years to date)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location: sa classe de française (her French class)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nadine:&lt;/strong&gt; Good morning, Madame. What would you say your favorite
Halloween candy is?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mme. Ferland:&lt;/strong&gt; Mini Crispy Crunch chocolate bars. That would
definitely be my favorite. I remember always having them in our family
as a treat we would get, so when I got free ones at Halloween, it was
always fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nadine:&lt;/strong&gt; Free stuff is just the best. What do you remember as your
most memorable Halloween?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mme. Ferland:&lt;/strong&gt; I think it was the first one where I didn’t have to go
with my parents. I actually got to go around the neighborhood with my
friends and that marked the beginning of me not having to go with my
parents anymore, so that was probably the most fun. Especially since we
were able to go off on our own. That was probably the most memorable
one. I was maybe ten at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nadine:&lt;/strong&gt; Merci!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr O’Reilly (has taught at MCI for 8 years to date)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location: His English classroom&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nadine:&lt;/strong&gt; What is your favorite Halloween candy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr O’Reilly (after careful consideration):&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve got to say, hands
down my all-time favorite are the mini Mars bars. No question. I’ll take
a box of Smarties, I’ll take a Coffee Crisp, but my all-time favorite is
the mini Mars bars. The last four years running I have bought Halloween
candy in advance to give out, but the Mars bars never make it to
Halloween. I eat them. I have a soft spot for them, and if I have the
opportunity, I’ll eat at least four of them. Like it’s bad, it’s a bad
habit I have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nadine:&lt;/strong&gt; And what about your most memorable Halloween?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr O’Reilly:&lt;/strong&gt; My most memorable Halloween? Gee-whiz, I spent three
years as a kid in Cleveland on Halloween trying to get my vampire down.
I couldn’t. I did a bad job on the vampire, but I think I got it the
last year I had it. I had it down, I even had fake blood on my cheek
&lt;em&gt;(motions to face)&lt;/em&gt; and white pancake makeup. I even got the makeup
right. I have a widows peak if you noticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** (reference picture to widows peak, delete after)**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nadine:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr O’Reilly:&lt;/strong&gt; So that is sort of essential [to the vampire
costume]. So the vampire was a good one. That stuck with me for a long
time. That’s all I can say. Another thing I want to mention is my
attitude about Halloween- it’s the best Holiday out of all of them. Why?
Because there’s no religious affiliation attached to it, there’s no
mystical meaning and it’s pretty easy to understand. Give candy to kids.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nadtelesford</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html">Two weeks before the beloved holiday where people wear elaborate costumes to scavenge every home in the neighborhood in search of the best candy possible, I interviewed some of the particularly festive teachers at MCI. To be specific, I interviewed the following teachers on their favorite candy and their most memorable Halloween experiences from when they were younger.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2023-10-23-Halloween-Interviews-With-MCI-Teachers.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/2023-10-23-Halloween-Interviews-With-MCI-Teachers.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What’s that Buzz around the Corner?</title><link href="/2023/10/The_Buzz-Around_That_Corner.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What’s that Buzz around the Corner?" /><published>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2023/10/The_Buzz-Around_That_Corner</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/10/The_Buzz-Around_That_Corner.html">&lt;p&gt;MCI has a problem. Students are being attacked at lunchtime by a
biological monstrosity that leaves no food untouched and no child
unstung. This despicable creature has students running for their lives,
following them all the way from Tim Hortons to MCI. Have you ever been
the victim of a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;wasp&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; attack? Wasps have been known from ancient
times to be the bane of students all over the world. Unfortunately, it
seems that wasps have taken a particular liking to MCI, as you can’t
even step outside of the school without being chased by a wasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wasps have also taken over the Tim Hortons next to MCI, as Haseib
Nasrat, a grade 11 student at Martingrove, learned the hard way. One
Friday afternoon, Haseib was peacefully waiting to order some Timmies,
when a wasp sitting on the windowsill decided Haseib was its enemy. The
wasp flew over and stung Haseib twice, on his shoulder and leg, which
caused him moderate pain. Naturally, Haseib did not enjoy this
experience, and when asked for his opinion on wasps, he stated, “Wasps
suck,” which is an opinion many MCI students, including myself,
wholeheartedly agree with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although wasps are usually the ones stinging students at MCI, their
friendlier counterparts, bees, often take the blame. As similar as they
seem, wasps should not be mixed up with bees. The biggest difference
between the two is their stings. Honey bees can only sting once, as
their barbed stinger gets stuck and torn off after they sting something,
which is typically fatal for them, so they only sting in self-defence.
Wasps, on the other hand, are often more aggressive than bees, as they
will attack anyone near their nest, and they can sting multiple times,
which is how Haseib knew he was stung by a wasp. Another big difference
between bees and wasps is what they eat. The diet of bees consists
simply of pollen and nectar, but wasps are bloodthirsty predators,
feasting on insects, larvae, and sometimes even MCI students!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, wasps and bees are pretty different, so the next time
you get chased by a flying demon, remember that it’s probably a wasp,
not a bee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bee safe Martingrove!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rpannu</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html">MCI has a problem. Students are being attacked at lunchtime by a biological monstrosity that leaves no food untouched and no child unstung. This despicable creature has students running for their lives, following them all the way from Tim Hortons to MCI. Have you ever been the victim of a wasp attack? Wasps have been known from ancient times to be the bane of students all over the world. Unfortunately, it seems that wasps have taken a particular liking to MCI, as you can’t even step outside of the school without being chased by a wasp.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2023-10-23-Whats-The-Buzz-Around-The-Corner.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/2023-10-23-Whats-The-Buzz-Around-The-Corner.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Rise of the School Instagram</title><link href="/2023/10/The_Rise_Of_The_School_Instagram_Page.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Rise of the School Instagram" /><published>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2023/10/The_Rise_Of_The_School_Instagram_Page</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/10/The_Rise_Of_The_School_Instagram_Page.html">&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, it seems like every school club, sports team, and everything
in between has an Instagram account. This has been going on for the past
couple years, but what caused this spike? In previous years, I didn’t
have Instagram and didn’t plan on getting it. However, when I entered
Grade 9, after my parents attended an information session, they
recommended that I should get it to keep up with the school community. I
didn’t see the reason behind this, but I downloaded the app anyway. I
noticed immediately how many accounts I would have to follow: MCI SAC,
MCI BAC, Relay for Life, the MCI &lt;em&gt;Beacon&lt;/em&gt;, and many more. It’s not only
MCI that has these accounts— other schools have them too. But the most
fascinating development has been the sports teams’ Instagram accounts.
Now, it seems like every team has an account. Some are good, some are
bad. But the all-time greatest sports Instagram account is the old MCI
hockey account. Run by the managers, ***INSERT NAMES*** , the page
conducted interviews and facilitated creative posts all season long, as
the entire school witnessed the greatest season in recent MCI history,
from the comfort of their phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all accounts are good, though. If you are old like me, you remember
the time an Instagram account that promoted hate and bullying was
investigated by the police. I still remember exactly where I was when
this was announced, as many senior MCI students do. Now, there are
accounts that post memes, but use a different model, as they promote
kindness and only post respectful memes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>mhutton</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html">Nowadays, it seems like every school club, sports team, and everything in between has an Instagram account. This has been going on for the past couple years, but what caused this spike? In previous years, I didn’t have Instagram and didn’t plan on getting it. However, when I entered Grade 9, after my parents attended an information session, they recommended that I should get it to keep up with the school community. I didn’t see the reason behind this, but I downloaded the app anyway. I noticed immediately how many accounts I would have to follow: MCI SAC, MCI BAC, Relay for Life, the MCI Beacon, and many more. It’s not only MCI that has these accounts— other schools have them too. But the most fascinating development has been the sports teams’ Instagram accounts. Now, it seems like every team has an account. Some are good, some are bad. But the all-time greatest sports Instagram account is the old MCI hockey account. Run by the managers, ***INSERT NAMES*** , the page conducted interviews and facilitated creative posts all season long, as the entire school witnessed the greatest season in recent MCI history, from the comfort of their phones.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2023-10-23-Rise-Of-The-School-Instagram.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/2023-10-23-Rise-Of-The-School-Instagram.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Doja Cat’s Scarlet: All Talk?</title><link href="/2023/10/scarlet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Doja Cat’s Scarlet: All Talk?" /><published>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2023/10/scarlet</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/10/scarlet.html">&lt;p&gt;After independently making music on Soundcloud in her teens, Doja Cat
was catapulted into superstardom upon the release of 2020’s &lt;em&gt;Say So&lt;/em&gt;: a
bubbly pop-rap anthem of early COVID years, soon followed by the
anticipated 2021 album, &lt;em&gt;Planet&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Her&lt;/em&gt;, featuring &lt;em&gt;Woman&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Need To
Know,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Kiss Me More&lt;/em&gt;. The world was ready for more of Doja’s music,
but her recent adoption of a demonic aesthetic, denouncement of previous
works, and harsh words towards ‘stans’ left a mixed public perception.
Alongside her controversies, a string of singles preceded her newest
album, &lt;em&gt;Scarlet&lt;/em&gt;, which was released this September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doja started strong with her lead single, and my personal album
highlight, &lt;em&gt;Attention&lt;/em&gt;. I’d sum the song up with the concluding line
from the first verse: “You follow me, but you don’t really care about
the music.” She is clearly criticising fans that believe they have a say
in her choices, deeming them as fake fans who don’t truly appreciate her
music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt optimistic about this new direction she was taking. &lt;em&gt;Attention&lt;/em&gt;
doesn’t fit into the homogenous &lt;em&gt;Planet Her&lt;/em&gt;, but unfortunately &lt;em&gt;Paint
The Town Red&lt;/em&gt; scurried back to the safety of her old style. &lt;em&gt;Paint The
Town Red&lt;/em&gt; is a collection of uninspired earworm hooks, and a vague
backlash against the notion of public martyrdom, yet it wasn’t as strong
as her previous successes. The subsequent single, &lt;em&gt;Demons&lt;/em&gt;, is yet again
about her public perception, while also lightly pushing her demonic
aesthetic, albeit more enjoyable than &lt;em&gt;Paint The Town Red&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On September 22nd, we finally got to hear the entirety of what &lt;em&gt;Scarlet&lt;/em&gt;
had to offer. Doja pushed back against fans who detracted her aesthetic,
retorting with “The only thing I sold was a record” in &lt;em&gt;Skull and
Bones&lt;/em&gt;. Doja also exercises some of her comical lyricism in songs like
&lt;em&gt;Can’t Wait&lt;/em&gt;, with weird quips like “I wanna be the stubborn crust of
barnacles around you” and, my personal favourite, “If you were to become
a Middle American farmer / I’d read up on every vegetable and harvest
them around you.” There is even a rare moment of her vulnerability when
she raps, “I hope that I can ease some the stress, can I chime in? / I
know I’ve been the root of the cause.” In some regards, &lt;em&gt;Scarlet&lt;/em&gt; did
not disappoint, with its entertaining moments sprinkled throughout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, that’s all they are: sprinkled. I had to scour for the
bars I quoted. My interest runs dry when I listen to tracks like &lt;em&gt;Gun&lt;/em&gt;,
where we get yet another song about a reproductive appendage without any
memorable or clever lines. The album became repetitive by restating the
same concepts about the same topics, which usually range between two
things: her fans and her fame. Her instrumental and lyrical growth
remain very limited, despite some slight stylistic and aesthetic
departure. The structure still remains the same: she releases a few
singles, some of which blow up, and the rest are filler. If her goal was
to lose her ‘fake fans’, then &lt;em&gt;Scarlet’s&lt;/em&gt; current dominance of #9 on
the &lt;em&gt;Billboard 200&lt;/em&gt; must mean very few were ‘fake’, but despite her PR
shenanigans, she’ll eventually lose the public’s &lt;em&gt;Attention&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>amisic</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html">After independently making music on Soundcloud in her teens, Doja Cat was catapulted into superstardom upon the release of 2020’s Say So: a bubbly pop-rap anthem of early COVID years, soon followed by the anticipated 2021 album, Planet Her, featuring Woman, Need To Know, and Kiss Me More. The world was ready for more of Doja’s music, but her recent adoption of a demonic aesthetic, denouncement of previous works, and harsh words towards ‘stans’ left a mixed public perception. Alongside her controversies, a string of singles preceded her newest album, Scarlet, which was released this September.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2023-10-23-Doja-Cat-Scarlet-All-Talk.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/2023-10-23-Doja-Cat-Scarlet-All-Talk.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>