<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-01T18:18:44-05:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Beacon</title><subtitle>The Beacon is Martingrove's newspaper.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A Year in Review: Ranking My Top 10 Films of 2019</title><link href="/2020/02/File.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Year in Review: Ranking My Top 10 Films of 2019" /><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/02/File</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/02/File.html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past twelve months, we were handed a diverse collection of
films. Be it comedies, thrillers, action movies, or dramas, filmmakers
new and old raised the bar for this medium in 2019. As the year comes to
an end, I am taking a look back and ranking my top ten movies of the
year. I chose the films that challenged me as a viewer, made me think
for days after I watched it, and most importantly, films that were just
really fun to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10. &lt;strong&gt;Climax&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Gasper Noé &lt;em&gt;Climax&lt;/em&gt; follows a group of aspiring
dancers in an abandoned school, as their rehearsal spirals out of
control into madness. This film is a visually stunning, yet disturbing
erotic rush from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9. &lt;strong&gt;Shazam!&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. David F. Sandberg From DC Comics, &lt;em&gt;Shazam&lt;/em&gt;! follows
14-year-old Billy Batson as he must learn how to deal with God-like
superpowers. With family values at the core of this film and a stellar
child cast, Shazam! is the most heartwarming superhero film of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8. &lt;strong&gt;Ad Astra&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. James Gray Brad Pitt soars in this film which
explores the powerful bond between a father and son. Cinematographer
Hoyte van Hoytema delivers a visual spectacle of outer space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7. &lt;strong&gt;The Peanut Butter Falcon&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Tyler Nilson, Michael Schwartz A
young man with down syndrome escapes his nursing facility with dreams of
attending a wrestling school. Shia LaBeouf is mesmerizing in this
charming homage to a Mark Twain classic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6. &lt;strong&gt;Midsommar&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Ari Aster &lt;em&gt;Midsommar&lt;/em&gt; is a confusing, thought
provoking, and ambitious film. Director Ari Aster creates another
masterfully crafted horror film that almost rivals Aster’s previous
classic, Hereditary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. &lt;strong&gt;The Lighthouse&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Robert Eggers Robert Pattinson and Willem
Dafoe give strong performances in this wicked tale of two lighthouse
keepers on a distant island in New England. Robert Eggers really
solidifies himself as a strong filmmaker in the horror genre with this
film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;Rocketman&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Dexter Fletcher Taron Egerton gives his best
performance yet with &lt;em&gt;Rocketman&lt;/em&gt;. I think it's going to be a long long
time until another film succeeds in creating a movie musical biopic as
intense as &lt;em&gt;Rocketman&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Booksmart&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Olivia Wilde Olivia Wilde’s directorial debut is a
coming-of-age comedy between two best friends and academic
‘overachievers’ who realize that they’ve wasted their high school years
slaving away instead of having fun. &lt;em&gt;Booksmart&lt;/em&gt; is a wild and fast-paced
movie that is clever in its portrayal of teenagers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Joker&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Todd Phillips &lt;em&gt;Joker&lt;/em&gt; is a heartbreaking and brutal
take on the clown prince of crime’s origin story. Todd Phillips draws
heavy inspiration from films such as Taxi Driver and The King of Comedy
to construct his tale of a man disregarded by society. Phillips’s Gotham
is corrupt and crime ridden, but it’s the realism that helps amplify the
film’s critique of a society that dismisses its citizens. Joaquin
Phoenix gives a disturbing performance as Arthur Fleck that at times may
call on the viewer to sympathize with him but strictly acknowledges his
vile actions. Todd Phillip’s direction and Lawrence Sher’s beautiful
cinematography accompanied by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?rlz=1C1CHBF_enCA725CA725&amp;amp;sxsrf=ACYBGNQuXgS18sMnW0dR0f5xf7FY-3OGsg:1573864416354&amp;amp;q=Hildur+Gu%C3%B0nad%C3%B3ttir&amp;amp;stick=H4sIAAAAAAAAAONgVuLSz9U3MKoyTMvIe8Toyi3w8sc9YSmbSWtOXmM04-IKzsgvd80rySypFNLgYoOy5Lj4pJC0aTBI8XAh8XkWsYp4ZOaklBYpuJce3pCXmHJ4c0lJZhEAfHynQG0AAAA&quot;&gt;Hildur
Guðnadóttir&lt;/a&gt;’s
hypnotizing score help make &lt;em&gt;Joker&lt;/em&gt; standout film from 2019 that must be
viewed more than once to fully grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Parasite&lt;/strong&gt; Dir. Bong Joon-ho Bong Joon-ho’s &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt; is
undoubtedly 2019’s must see film. Every aspect of this film from its
cast to its cinematography is fantastic. &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt;’s depiction of
themes of class, wealth, and dignity are apparent but not in your face.
Joon-ho’s slow yet persistent race to the end will keep you on the edge
of your seat. &lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt; follows the extremely poor Kim family as they
launch an all-out assault on the blatantly wealthy Park family. When
Kim’s son, Ki-Woo, secures a job as a tutor for the daughter of the Park
family, he opens the door for the rest of his family to infiltrate the
Park’s home. The Kim family makes quick work of ridding the Park
family’s employees and securing their jobs through tactical and cunning
plans. Each member of the Kim family has a moment to shine. The film
starts off presenting itself as a satirical comedy but takes a jarring
turn into brutality. The film spirals out of control in front of your
eyes and you are forced to view every disturbing second of it. Bong’s
mastery of the camera and formulation of violence is electrifying in
&lt;em&gt;Parasite&lt;/em&gt;. This film is truly an unforgettable piece of cinema will be
deconstructed, examined, and celebrated for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/50048137@N00/8442936606&quot;&gt;&quot;Welcome To The
Theater&quot;&lt;/a&gt; by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/50048137@N00&quot;&gt;rsmithing&lt;/a&gt; is licensed
under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;amp;atype=rich&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC 2.0
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ifuse-katayama</name></author><summary type="html">Over the past twelve months, we were handed a diverse collection of films. Be it comedies, thrillers, action movies, or dramas, filmmakers new and old raised the bar for this medium in 2019. As the year comes to an end, I am taking a look back and ranking my top ten movies of the year. I chose the films that challenged me as a viewer, made me think for days after I watched it, and most importantly, films that were just really fun to watch.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2020-02-01-File_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Don Cherry Divide</title><link href="/2020/02/The_Don_Cherry_Divide.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Don Cherry Divide" /><published>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/02/The_Don_Cherry_Divide</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/02/The_Don_Cherry_Divide.html">&lt;p&gt;The winter holidays are a time to embrace the spirit of togetherness, be
merry, and spend time with family. Unfortunately, something happened in
November that has quickly become one of the most heated issues in Canada
(and could lead to awkward conversations with the extended family around
the dinner table). This event was the firing of Don Cherry. You’ve
probably heard about this, but in case you haven’t, here is a brief
rundown of what happened. On Remembrance Day, the 85-year-old NHL
commentator went after immigrants in Toronto and Mississauga, accusing
them of not wearing poppies and not honouring Canada’s veterans.
Undoubtedly the part that drew the most criticism was his use of the
words “you people.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The statement quickly drew widespread criticism, and Sportsnet fired Don
Cherry. Don Cherry, throughout his history as a broadcaster, has had a
history of making very controversial statements. These instances include
the time when he complained about “wom[e]n yapping away” at hockey
games or when he said vulgar things about Liberals at the 2010 inaugural
meeting of Toronto’s new city council, describing the Liberal media as
“left-wing pinkos”, and “kooks”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that may have contributed to Cherry’s firing was his
unwillingness to apologize. In an interview he did with Fox News, he
said that he might have used different wording if he could have done it
over, but came nowhere near giving a formal apology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only were Cherry’s comments offensive, but they were inaccurate and
counterproductive. While the sentiment of getting people to appreciate
all that our veterans have sacrificed for Canada is good, Cherry failed
to take into account that immigrants are also part of the Canadian
military. Sergeant Stephen Thomas, 37, is a first-generation Canadian
with parents from Guyana, who served two tours in Afghanistan, and was
shocked by Cherry’s comments. He said: “I don’t think he’s realized how
much the military has changed over the last decade or two.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason Don Cherry was fired was that his comments, whether
intentional or unintentional (as his supporters claim), hurt people. His
racist, sexist, and rude comments throughout the years may have been few
and far between, but the fact that he was unwilling to apologize says a
lot about his character. His firing is a stepping stone in slowly
getting rid of the voices of discrimination better left in the past. On
this holiday, in the spirit of togetherness, we should all recognize
what Cherry could not - that no matter what country we were born in, we
are all Canadian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.behance.net/gallery/3455711/Hockey-Night-in-Canada&quot;&gt;&quot;Hockey Night in
Canada&quot;&lt;/a&gt;
by Franco Barroeta is licensed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;amp;atype=rich&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC-ND 4.0
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>mhutzul</name></author><summary type="html">The winter holidays are a time to embrace the spirit of togetherness, be merry, and spend time with family. Unfortunately, something happened in November that has quickly become one of the most heated issues in Canada (and could lead to awkward conversations with the extended family around the dinner table). This event was the firing of Don Cherry. You’ve probably heard about this, but in case you haven’t, here is a brief rundown of what happened. On Remembrance Day, the 85-year-old NHL commentator went after immigrants in Toronto and Mississauga, accusing them of not wearing poppies and not honouring Canada’s veterans. Undoubtedly the part that drew the most criticism was his use of the words “you people.”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2020-02-01-The_Don_Cherry_Divide_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Winter Wonderland</title><link href="/2019/12/A_Winter_Wonderland_-_Nicole_Yotis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Winter Wonderland" /><published>2019-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2019/12/A_Winter_Wonderland_-_Nicole_Yotis</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/12/A_Winter_Wonderland_-_Nicole_Yotis.html">&lt;p&gt;Winter is my favourite season, without a doubt. The snow makes
everything look so picturesque and the break is right on our doorstep.
However, for some people, the holidays are dull, with no school to
occupy their days, and friends gone on vacations. But fear not, there
are still so many things to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anything snow-related:&lt;/strong&gt; Take advantage of the season and get out
there. Build a snowman, go sledding or skating, or have a snowball
fight. Winter is also the time to ski, or try something more
outlandish, like ice fishing or snow sculpting. One of my favourite
things to do is build a snow fort with my friends. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indoor activities:&lt;/strong&gt; However fun it is to play in the snow, it’s
cold. But inside, you can make crafts (a great gift idea), catch up
on your reading, draw (the snowy landscape will provide lots of
inspiration), or learn to cook something new. Also, drink hot
chocolate, especially after playing in the snow (that’s the best
time to drink it).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go to a concert:&lt;/strong&gt; There are lots of concerts in December, many
with holiday themes. So whether you’d like to go see your favourite
artist, or maybe go somewhere new, there will definitely be
something to peak your interest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Catch up with old friends:&lt;/strong&gt; I have many friends from elementary
school who I haven’t seen in a long time. The break is a great time
to reach out and plan a time to get together. And if you don’t know
what to do when you see them, perhaps you should try something from
this list. Happy holidays!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/90173772@N00/4215323902&quot;&gt;&quot;Merry
Christmas!&quot;&lt;/a&gt; by xymox is
licensed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;amp;atype=rich&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC-ND
2.0 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nyotis</name></author><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html">Winter is my favourite season, without a doubt. The snow makes everything look so picturesque and the break is right on our doorstep. However, for some people, the holidays are dull, with no school to occupy their days, and friends gone on vacations. But fear not, there are still so many things to do.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2019-12-22-A_Winter_Wonderland_-_Nicole_Yotis_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Grinch Was the Victim</title><link href="/2019/12/The_Grinch_Was_the_Victim_-_Ambika_Mehta.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Grinch Was the Victim" /><published>2019-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2019/12/The_Grinch_Was_the_Victim_-_Ambika_Mehta</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/12/The_Grinch_Was_the_Victim_-_Ambika_Mehta.html">&lt;p&gt;When the Grinch was just a baby&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was left rejected and dangling from a tree&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While he watched the people of WHOville&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attend the annual Christmas party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resilient of the traumatizing events&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Grinch continued his life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until he met Martha May&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And hoped to one day, make her his wife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the Grinch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an outcast in society,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He decided to gather up his courage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And pursue Martha wholeheartedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoping that Martha would see past his rich&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;green skin and hair aplenty,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had an idea that brought him nothing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what felt like notoriety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poor Grinch stayed up all night creating&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The perfect gift for Martha, a girl he adored,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But was made fun of by Augustus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MayWHO, who’s irrelevant entity needed to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;be ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Grinch cut his face when he tried&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;shaving his hair&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when he returned to school&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was surrounded by laughter everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I hate Christmas, I HaTe It!” the Grinch would say,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But he failed to realize that the people of WHOville were phonies
anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They made the Grinch feel unwanted and were materialistic fools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their hearts were small and were straight up cruel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He isolated himself from the people of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WHOville and went to live on top of Mount Crumpit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was accompanied by his dog, Max&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who was always there for him, lickety split&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Grinch’s heart went from big to small in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a matter of time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He grew older and became sour as lime&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had a plan to wreck Christmas for everyone in the town&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But WHO could blame him, the Grinch was a genius, and deserved a crown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was one thing that needed to be served, and that was justice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particularly from the snotty bully named Augustus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Augustus became the mayor of the small town,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But little did he know it was all going &lt;em&gt;doowwn&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fastforward, the mayor proposed to Martha in front of the Grinch,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it wasn't until Martha said “My heart belongs to someone else”,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;that the Grinch’s heart grew more than an inch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion the people of WHOville suck&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the Grinch has nice lashes. The End.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/66478195@N00/6541151793&quot;&gt;&quot;Meeting the
Grinch&quot;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/66478195@N00&quot;&gt;Castles,
Capes &amp;amp; Clones&lt;/a&gt; is licensed
under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;amp;atype=rich&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC-ND
2.0 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>amehta</name></author><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html">When the Grinch was just a baby</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2019-12-22-The_Grinch_Was_the_Victim_-_Ambika_Mehta_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Say What You Mean, Mean What You Say</title><link href="/2019/12/Say_what_you_mean_mean_what_you_say_-_Nicole_Yotis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Say What You Mean, Mean What You Say" /><published>2019-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2019/12/Say_what_you_mean_mean_what_you_say_-_Nicole_Yotis</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/12/Say_what_you_mean_mean_what_you_say_-_Nicole_Yotis.html">&lt;p&gt;If you’re not already aware, we are living in an age where everything is
available at our fingertips. News, entertainment, music, etc. - with
just the push of a button it’s all there. However, with this newfound
freedom comes a price that I’m sure you’re already aware of. What we say
online is usually different, sometimes to an extreme, than what we say
in real life. Most of the warnings that we hear about online safety
include never giving away your personal information, or being mindful of
what it is you’re saying. But what we don’t hear about as often is how
your personality itself can change. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say that you’re on an app that connects you to other people (your
friends, family, even strangers), and you suddenly see something that
interests you. Immediately you feel the need to comment something, right
then. The world must know about what you have to say. So, you type a
quick comment. Soon, you get a reply and are suddenly having a
conversation on a topic that you, in fact, don’t really know much about.
So what do you do? Keep having the conversation? It seems as though
there’s no other choice. You can’t just log off and leave people
hanging. So you keep talking, thinking it doesn’t matter. Who cares if
you’re wrong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This very well might not be you. But the truth is, some people just feel
the need to talk, so, knowing that they’ll never actually meet the
person they’re talking to and knowing they’re not going to have to
actually face the consequences of giving said person misinformation,
they just keep going. This is really something you need to be watchful
of. Telling other people something that isn’t true and presenting it as
fact can mislead lots of people, and can also harm your reputation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe, instead of talking off the top of your head, you speak in
extremes. You might say that you hate something that you see, but really
just mildly dislike it. Or perhaps you see something that makes you
chuckle a bit, and then say that it was so funny that you were dying of
laughter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exaggerating is an easy thing to do on the internet. You want people to
like what you say, to agree with you. So instead of giving an honest
reply, you turn your comment into something it’s not, solely for the
sake of making more people agree with you. This isn’t a really terrible
thing, but try to keep it real. While it’s okay to exaggerate a bit, you
might end up having a real conversation when you dial it down a few
notches too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing people do online is be completely silent. Now this may
not sound as bad, and it isn’t a big problem, especially compared to the
other things I’ve been writing about. But you do have social media to
be, well, social. Don’t be so afraid to say something that it keeps you
from saying anything entirely. A good thing to keep in mind when
interacting with others on the internet is to say something positive, as
opposed to negative. And if someone says something negative to you, try
to be mature. You don’t have to reply, but if you do, make sure that you
aren’t being rude or impolite. The best thing to do is just let it go.
You didn’t do anything wrong, the other person did, so don’t let them
bother you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, just pay attention to what exactly it is that you’re saying
online. It’s quite easy to misinterpret what anyone could say when it’s
written down, as you don’t have facial expressions or emphasis to guide
you. So be careful, and try to assume the best. You catch more flies
with honey than vinegar.
egar.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nyotis</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">If you’re not already aware, we are living in an age where everything is available at our fingertips. News, entertainment, music, etc. - with just the push of a button it’s all there. However, with this newfound freedom comes a price that I’m sure you’re already aware of. What we say online is usually different, sometimes to an extreme, than what we say in real life. Most of the warnings that we hear about online safety include never giving away your personal information, or being mindful of what it is you’re saying. But what we don’t hear about as often is how your personality itself can change. </summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Psychology Behind New Year’s Resolutions, and Why Many Don’t Fulfill Them</title><link href="/2019/12/Resolutions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Psychology Behind New Year's Resolutions, and Why Many Don’t Fulfill Them" /><published>2019-12-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2019/12/Resolutions</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/12/Resolutions.html">&lt;p&gt;A lot happens in a year. Each person undergoes easy and hard times,
facing both triumph and defeat. This makes up for the time spent
thinking, working, and scrambling to get through it all. By December,
many people are exhausted, and wish to start over. Awaiting them is a
new year. The prospect of something new makes us feel like there’s
nothing we can’t do, because anything is possible for the future. Thus,
we reflect on our past year, and figure out what to do differently from
now on. With this come our resolutions. People get excited about the
changes they will make to better themselves and their lives. Many can’t
wait for New Years, and all the apparent bliss that comes with it.
However, after New Years, what happens to these resolutions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt;, studies have shown that less than &lt;strong&gt;25%&lt;/strong&gt; of
individuals stay committed to their New Year's Resolutions after &lt;strong&gt;just
30 days,&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;only 8%&lt;/strong&gt; actually accomplish them. These statistics
give rise to the question: why don’t people keep their resolutions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People tend to fall back into old habits. After the atmosphere of
optimism surrounding New Years is gone, people will return to the same
lifestyles they led before without a thought. Even if they want to alter
an aspect of their life, they will live in the same way, and forget
about their resolutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, we forget that making changes in life takes effort. A lot of
people are not willing to try for the small things they want. Sticking
to a resolution is easier said than done, and people feel better not
attempting something, than trying and possibly failing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, there is not much motivation to go through with one’s
resolutions. New Years is smack in the middle of winter, which is a
season of comfort. The feelings of laziness and sleepiness we feel make
it difficult to want to do anything. This is especially true if your
resolution includes getting out of the house. It is easy to get tempted
by a warm sofa or a new &lt;em&gt;Netflix&lt;/em&gt; movie instead of stepping out into the
snow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/40939157@N03/31609901167&quot;&gt;&quot;Happy New
Year&quot;&lt;/a&gt; by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/40939157@N03&quot;&gt;nigelhowe&lt;/a&gt; is licensed
under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;amp;atype=rich&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC 2.0
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>smahmud</name></author><summary type="html">A lot happens in a year. Each person undergoes easy and hard times, facing both triumph and defeat. This makes up for the time spent thinking, working, and scrambling to get through it all. By December, many people are exhausted, and wish to start over. Awaiting them is a new year. The prospect of something new makes us feel like there’s nothing we can’t do, because anything is possible for the future. Thus, we reflect on our past year, and figure out what to do differently from now on. With this come our resolutions. People get excited about the changes they will make to better themselves and their lives. Many can’t wait for New Years, and all the apparent bliss that comes with it. However, after New Years, what happens to these resolutions?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2019-12-06-Resolutions_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Time to be Empowered</title><link href="/2019/11/November__A_Time_to_be_Empowered.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Time to be Empowered" /><published>2019-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2019/11/November__A_Time_to_be_Empowered</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/11/November__A_Time_to_be_Empowered.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November: A Time to be Empowered&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rhea Matharu&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grade 11 Copy Editor &amp;amp; Production Head&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe, in order to be empowered to take action about this unrevealed
(for now) issue, you will need to be in a different perspective. Close
your eyes and read the following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You begin as a piece of cheap fabric that required 2700 litres of water
(an average person drinks this in 2.5 years). The workers are tired,
struggling with scars on their hands, to piece you together for a living
wage. However, you are only &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;many&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;em&gt;About&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;140 billion
garments&lt;/strong&gt; *are manufactured each year. The amount of resources spent on
you account for nothing as you have a short lifespan. Your impact? You
produced 1.2 billion tonnes of CO2 (per year), yet end up in a landfill
producing more methane. *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This horrifying perspective effectively portrays the product life cycle
that a fast fashion piece of garment experiences. This exposes the
perceived benefit of $20 jeans that last for a very short amount of
time due to its cheap materials. This short lifespan is largely because
of brands like Forever21, Zara, and H&amp;amp;M wanting to match the growing
demand for new, trendy clothing, resulting in new clothing designs and
styles being created every few weeks! Instead of two season cycles,
there are at least 52 seasons for clothing in the fast fashion industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have learned about the harms of the fashion industry, learn
about what you, the consumer, can do to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduce the amount of clothing you buy from fast fashion stores, or
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;even better, stop shopping there altogether. Shop from thrift
stores or stores that sustainably produce their items. The
decreasing demand is sure to change their manufacturing processes.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instead of throwing out your clothing, donate it to stores that
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;accept them or your friends/family. Before buying your clothes,
make sure you know that you will wear it a significant amount of
times.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Reach out to these fast fashion brands to express your concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spread awareness to people you know to expose the hidden truths
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;behind these companies.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This November, empower yourself and others to create less carbon
emissions. The fast fashion industry is one of the largest contributors,
if not the largest, to climate change. Surprisingly, it is not one that
people think of. It’s harm on the planet and terrible working conditions
in factories must be put to an end.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rmatharu</name></author><summary type="html">November: A Time to be Empowered</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2019-11-12-November__A_Time_to_be_Empowered_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Advice on Mornings</title><link href="/2019/11/Advice_on_Mornings_by_April_Naing_1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advice on Mornings" /><published>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2019/11/Advice_on_Mornings_by_April_Naing_1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/11/Advice_on_Mornings_by_April_Naing_1.html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s face it. Most of us aren’t morning people, and with school
starting again a lot of us aren’t used to waking up at the crack of
dawn. Gone are the days when we could sleep until noon and constantly
press “snooze”. However mornings aren’t the worst! In fact, they can
actually be quite nice. They’re quiet and peaceful. The air seems
fresher and catching a sunrise is always a welcome sight. You might even
have a bit of time to be productive! So without further ado, here are
some tips so you can maximize your mornings!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go to sleep earlier!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is pretty straightforward. You need adequate sleep to maintain
your health and sanity! What if you have an assignment? Try sleeping
earlier and then waking up earlier to finish it before school starts.
Help your circadian rhythm by sticking to a regular sleep schedule
including on weekends!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting/choosing an alarm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, annoying alarms will get you up but it’ll also put you in a bad
mood to start your morning. It’ll leave you feeling murderous. Talk
about waking up on the wrong side of your bed...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wake up earlier than you normally do&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that when my alarm goes off getting up is crucial. Lingering
under your covers might be tempting but it also makes you feel more
sluggish and loses precious time for your body to get used to being
awake before you’re off to class. Force yourself to get out of bed!
It’ll depend on each person but 6am-7am is a good time to wake up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open your curtains!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural lighting = very good. Crack open your window for fresh air and
to hear the birds chirp!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Put on some music!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music can set up the atmosphere and instantly improve your mood in the
morning! You could play your favorite jam to get you pumped up or a nice
soundtrack for a calming and happy effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water is your best friend&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your body hasn’t had any water for hours by now! Down a glass of fresh
H₂O to rehydrate and splash your face with cold water to get refreshed.
You can opt for a quick shower too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breakfast isn’t negotiable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re like me you’re probably guilty of skipping this vital part of
your mornings. A healthy breakfast improves your memory and mood and
helps you stay concentrated. It’s key for productivity. Recently I’ve
leaned towards a small bowl of cereal or toast, some fruit and a cup of
green tea or coffee!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people may find a walk or run in the morning really helps
especially in the morning when the air feels fresher. Or just brave an
ice cold shower and get a mini heart attack. A warm shower might just
make your drowsier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan your day!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to a good end is a good start! Jot down a to-do list in your
bullet journal, agenda, phone or just think about it on your commute.
Alternatively you can have a morning journal to write your thoughts or
keep track of your dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BONUS (Apps to try out!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sleepyti.me:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a sleep calculator that really works! You’ll
feel more refreshed in the day if you don’t wake up in the middle of a
sleep cycle. Sleepyti.me helps you to wake up at the optimal time so
that you don’t interrupt any cycles!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WhiteNoise:&lt;/strong&gt; WhiteNoise is a free app that gives you a ton of tracks
and calming sounds to choose from that will play from your phone to help
you sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pacifica:&lt;/strong&gt; This one is for if you’re feeling stressed or anxious.
Includes trackers and exercises to try. You can also use it to talk to
others who are feeling the same stress. It’s a free app too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image via Flickr&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>anaing</name></author><summary type="html">Let’s face it. Most of us aren’t morning people, and with school starting again a lot of us aren’t used to waking up at the crack of dawn. Gone are the days when we could sleep until noon and constantly press “snooze”. However mornings aren’t the worst! In fact, they can actually be quite nice. They’re quiet and peaceful. The air seems fresher and catching a sunrise is always a welcome sight. You might even have a bit of time to be productive! So without further ado, here are some tips so you can maximize your mornings!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2019-11-10-Advice_on_Mornings_by_April_Naing_1_photo.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lest We Forget</title><link href="/2019/11/April_Naing_-_Remembrance_Day-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lest We Forget" /><published>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2019/11/April_Naing_-_Remembrance_Day-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/11/April_Naing_-_Remembrance_Day-2.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remembrance Day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remembrance Day &lt;em&gt;(Jour du Souvenir)&lt;/em&gt; is observed annually on November
11, the anniversary marking the end of World War 1. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The First World War was the largest conflict the world had ever seen at
the time. The war was a result of many factors, including political
tension and military alliances. The assassination of Archduke Franz
Ferdinand of Austria in 1914 sparked the beginning of a crisis and the
war began that same year in August. It would become a bloody four year
war with close to 61,000 Canadians killed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally the day was called “Armistice Day” to commemorate the
armistice agreement which ended the war on Monday, November 11, 1918, at
11 a.m, the eleventh hour of the eleventh day of the eleventh month. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vimy Ridge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considered Canada’s most celebrated Canadian military victory, the
battle of Vimy Ridge was fought from the 9th to 12th of April 1917 on
the Western Front of northern France. Four divisions of the Canadian
Corps fought united and captured the ridge from the German army. It was
the largest territorial advance of any Allied force at that point in the
war. Unfortunately the cost of the victory was overwhelming; more than
10,600 Canadians were killed or wounded in the battle. Today a memorial
stands at the top of the ridge to honour the 11,285 Canadians killed in
France throughout the war who have no marked graves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remembering &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day serves to remember all the lives that were lost in the line of
duty and the countless sacrifices soldiers made to uphold international
peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically there is a National Ceremony on the date each year at the
National War Memorial in Ottawa. It is nationally televised and attended
by the Prime Minister, government officials, veterans organizations’
representatives, diplomatic representatives, dignitaries, veterans as
well as the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Can You Do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•Remember those who served and the fallen. Honour their sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•Have a respectful moment of silence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•Wear the Remembrance Day symbol, a poppy, with the &lt;em&gt;correct etiquette&lt;/em&gt;,
that is: on the left over your heart, from the last Friday in October
until November 11&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/34534185@N00/48685673082&quot;&gt;&quot;Remembrance Day
Poppy_2=&quot;&lt;/a&gt; by Sheba_Also
46000 + photos-Videos is licensed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;amp;atype=rich&quot;&gt;CC BY-SA
2.0 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
ich)*&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>anaing</name></author><summary type="html">Remembrance Day</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2019-11-10-April_Naing_-_Remembrance_Day-2_photo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How Independent Are You? A Quiz for Young Adults Who Think They’re Ready To Be Adults</title><link href="/2019/11/Independent.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Independent Are You? A Quiz for Young Adults Who Think They’re Ready To Be Adults" /><published>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2019/11/Independent</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/11/Independent.html">&lt;p&gt;For several years, we, the students of MCI, have had, for the most part,
a simple structure to our lives. Wake up. Go to school. Eat. Sleep.
Climb a level in the education system (ideally) annually. Spend your
free time as you like it. This is the regular childhood and adolescence
of most suburban youth. We are extraordinarily lucky to be living in a
time and place that allows us to mature in such a slow, gentle manner.
But like it or not, time is taking us closer to adulthood, buckaroos.
Whether it’s dragging you, by the hair, or softly carrying you, we all
have the same destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And let’s face it, some of us are more ready to become “functioning
members of society” than others. Are you one of them? Let’s see how many
bears are ready to tackle the hardships of a grown-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This quiz is, of course, purely for fun. Don’t bother to cheat or look
up anything. Save your calories for a math test. Answers are at the end!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Ideally&lt;/em&gt;, you should be putting at least __ of your earnings
aside as savings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  5% &lt;strong&gt;b)&lt;/strong&gt; 10% &lt;strong&gt;c)&lt;/strong&gt; 15% &lt;strong&gt;d)&lt;/strong&gt; 20% &lt;strong&gt;e)&lt;/strong&gt; 30%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; While deep frying french fries, some oil spills on the gas
stovetop and catches fire. Both your countertop and the pot of oil are
on fire! What is the best way (aside from using a fire extinguisher) to
put it out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Pour a deep bowl of water on all the flames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b)  Turn off the heat and smother fires with metal (a metal pot lid,
    &amp;gt; baking sheet, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c)  Move the pot outside, spray water on the countertop and call 911.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;d)  Sprinkle a little baking soda on the fires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Which of the following is NOT at all covered by OHIP?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Emergency healthcare &lt;strong&gt;b)&lt;/strong&gt; Casts and crutches&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c)&lt;/strong&gt; Dental surgeries (in a hospital) &lt;strong&gt;d)&lt;/strong&gt; Hospital stays&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; What does GIC stand for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Guaranteed Investment Certificate &lt;strong&gt;b)&lt;/strong&gt; The newest Kpop group&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c)&lt;/strong&gt; Generalized Intensive Care &lt;strong&gt;d)&lt;/strong&gt; Green Innovation Committee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt; What is the first tool to reach for when your toilet is clogged?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  cup plunger &lt;strong&gt;b)&lt;/strong&gt; flange plunger&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c)&lt;/strong&gt; toilet brush &lt;strong&gt;d)&lt;/strong&gt; a wire clothing hanger from Walmart&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.&lt;/strong&gt; Which of these should NOT be stored in the fridge?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Raw zucchini &lt;strong&gt;b)&lt;/strong&gt; Whole, unpeeled onions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c)&lt;/strong&gt; Green beans &lt;strong&gt;d)&lt;/strong&gt; Cut portobello mushrooms&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.&lt;/strong&gt; The best stitch for strength and security (and mending clothes)
is the _______.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Straight stitch &lt;strong&gt;b)&lt;/strong&gt; Backstitch &lt;strong&gt;c)&lt;/strong&gt; Running stitch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;d)&lt;/strong&gt; Hidden stitch &lt;strong&gt;e)&lt;/strong&gt; Cross stitch &lt;strong&gt;f)&lt;/strong&gt; Whip stitch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.&lt;/strong&gt; How often is it recommended that you clean/change your bedding?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Every 1-2 weeks &lt;strong&gt;b)&lt;/strong&gt; Every month&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c)&lt;/strong&gt; Every 2 months &lt;strong&gt;d)&lt;/strong&gt; It doesn’t matter, as long as it looks
clean and doesn’t smell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9.&lt;/strong&gt; When is electricity the cheapest in Ontario?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Before 7 am and after 7 pm, weekdays&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b)  11 am to 5 pm, weekdays&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c)  Weekends and holidays&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;d)  Electricity is the same price at any time of the day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;e)  Both a and c&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10.&lt;/strong&gt; Who can ask you for your SIN (Social Insurance Number)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Your college/university admissions office&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b)  Your landlord, negotiating a lease with you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c)  Your (confirmed) employer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;d)  No one but the government&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all I have for you now! Hopefully you did well. If not, don’t
worry-you still have time to learn. Most people pick this kind of stuff
up as they go, anyway. Though this couldn’t have gone too badly. I
didn’t even put any questions on doing taxes. Maybe next issue~?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Answers: **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.(d) 2.(b) 3.(b) 4.(a) 5.(b) 6.(b) 7.(b) 8.(a) 9.(e) 10.(c)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image via Shutterstock&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>lli</name></author><summary type="html">For several years, we, the students of MCI, have had, for the most part, a simple structure to our lives. Wake up. Go to school. Eat. Sleep. Climb a level in the education system (ideally) annually. Spend your free time as you like it. This is the regular childhood and adolescence of most suburban youth. We are extraordinarily lucky to be living in a time and place that allows us to mature in such a slow, gentle manner. But like it or not, time is taking us closer to adulthood, buckaroos. Whether it’s dragging you, by the hair, or softly carrying you, we all have the same destination.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/2019-11-10-Independent_photo.jpg" /></entry></feed>